<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-jack-the-ripper</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85058130/1888-11-27/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Jack+Ripper</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              A private person living near NottiD2
              ham has received a letter signed Jack
              Rippers pal stating that both the
              writer of the letter and Jack com
              mitted the recent murders in White
              Chapel district The writer says Jack
              is a Bavarian whom he first met
              aboard a ship returning from America
              and who exercised a mesmerjstic in
              fluence
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82014381/1888-12-18/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Jack+Ripper</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              JACK, THE RIPPER."
              A Montreal Crank, Who ig Probably a
              Ripping Liar.
              Montreal, December 17th.—A man has
              been arrested here for assaulting a woman,
              who says he is "Jack, the Ripper." This
              evening, a3 Miss Florier Newcome was
              was walking on Lagauchetorie street, in a
              dark quarter of the city, a man suddenly
              dartea out of a gateway and caught her by
              the arm, exclaiming: "You must come
              with me!" The girl screamed, and break
              ing away, rushed along the treet, closely
              followed by the man.
              This man, when arrested, said: "I'm
              Jack, the Ripper! All Whitcchapel is
              looking for me! I have just arrived. I
              intended to give myself up, as I have
              alrtadly killed fifteen, and I'll yet com
              plete the number if you let me go. You'd
              better hang me by the neck till I'm dead ?"
              He had a big knife, and said his real
              name was John Langhorn, aged 25,0f Lon
              don. He is detained for further examina
              tion.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86064205/1888-12-22/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Jack+Ripper</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              STANLEY SAFE
              Ileliable IVews That He Has Arrived
              ¬
              on the Aruwini
              Another Murder of a Woman in London
              is Charged to the Whitechapel
              Fiend Jack the Ripper
              Ulaineas Minister to GermanyThe English
              Troops at Suakim An Eflectlve Blockade
              Sustained at Hajti
              ZAJSZlllAltA letter from Henry jr Stanley Hated Audust 10 What He Was Doing Then
              London Dec 21 Advices from Zanzibar
              ¬
              say a letter dated Stanley Falls
              August 19 lias been delivered here byTyphoo Tibs men They stato
              that the letter was received
              it Stanley Falls from Henry
              m Stanley AugurfU Stanley was then
              at I ouyala on o Auwuimi where ho
              had arrived Augi t 17 He had left
              Kmin Pasha eightytwo days before iu
              perfect health andprovided with plenty
              of food Stanley had returned to Bouyaia for the stores iu charge of his rearguard and intended to leave ten days
              later to rejoin Emin Ho reported all tlie
              whites in the expedition as healthy and
              said tlie expedition wanted nothing
              London Dec 21 Anolllcial order is
              published instructing the British consul
              at Zanzibar to issue regulations for tho
              government of British subjects there and
              empowering the consul to punish violations
              ¬
              thereof by lines or iuiprisotneutTlie West Atrican Telegraph Company
              has received the following dispatch from
              St Thomas dated Friday 2 pm I
              have just received information that Henry
              ¬
              L M Stanley with Emin Pasha Ijas
              arrived on the Aruwini The news is reliable Further details will follow
              Signed Paksons Agent
              rSOLAXl
              The Whileehapel riend lias Adopted a Veio
              Hut Hffeetive Seheme
              London Dec 21 Tho body of a
              woman whoso name is unknown was
              found yesterday morning iu tho streets of
              Poplar in tlie suburbs of London An
              empty phial lay alongside tho body and
              the impression first formed was that tho
              woman had committed suicide At tho
              coroners inquest today however physicians
              ¬
              who examined tho body testified
              that there were no signs of poison in tho
              stomach and declared their belief
              that tho woman had been
              murdered by strangulation They said
              the condition of tho body justified this
              belief and in addition to this there was n
              mark on tho womans neck which showed
              a small cord had been tied tightly around
              it The woman was of a low character
              When tho body was found it was still
              warm It was lying in an open street
              and there is no possibility that tho woman
              could have taken her own lrfo Some
              persons believe that her murderer is identical
              ¬
              with tho Whitechapel fiend who
              they think has adopted a new method of
              disposing of his victims
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1888-12-22/ed-1/seq-1//#words=Jack+Ripper+body+dead+murder</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              y.*1
              IS IT "JACK THE RIPPER" AGAIN ?
              IAN0THEK FALLEN WOMAN FOUND MiCRDlSREP
              IN A PimrRB OF LONDON.
              London, Dec. 21..The body of a woman, wbo«-e
              name li unknown, was found yeatendbf morning in Unstreets of Poplar, In the suburbs of London. An
              empty vial lay alongside the b.idv, and the impres¬
              sion first formed wa* that the woman had committed
              suicide. At the covonor's inquest lo-day, however,
              the physicians who examined the bed] leettfied that
              there were no signs of poison in the stomach, and de¬
              clared -heir belief that the woman had bass murdered
              by strangulation. They said the condition of the
              body Justified this belief, and In addition to that
              there was a mark on the woman's neck which showi-«l
              that a cmall cord had been Bad tightly around th Tba
              woman was of low cha-ra-cte.r. What the lumv tifound lt wa» fill warm. Il was lying in an __(>en
              thoroughfaire, ard there ls r.o poealbuitj that th»^
              woman coule hav.. taloen her own life. Some persons
              believe that her murderer ls Identical with thfl Wt-techapel ficml. wh/,, the-y think, has adopted .i
              method of disposing of his v*,t.lms.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90059522/1888-12-27/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Jack+Ripper</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              CUT UP TE CORPSE.
              A Philadelphia Murderer Emj ulates the Example of
              Jack the Ripper.
              He Dismembers His Victim
              and Puts the Pieces
              in Packages.
              Forty Innocent Children Ravished by a Physician
              in Escanaba.
              Crazed by Grief, a Cincinnati
              Jurist Slows Out His
              Brains.
              Philadelphia, Dee. 26.—Aparty of
              boys, while playing in East Fairmount
              park to-day, in the vicinity of the new city reservoir, founa two bundles in a section of the new thirty-six-inch water
              main stored there. For curiosity's sake, one of the boys cut the string of one of
              the bundles, and was horrified when a human head rolled out. The police au- thorities were at once notified, and further investigation developed the fact
              that the bundle first opened also con- tained the dismembered trunk of a hu- man body. The other bundle, on being opened, disclosed the nude legs belonging to the trunk found in the other
              package. Evidently a most horrible
              murder had been committed, and the
              condition ofthe remains indicated that
              the deed had been done within twenty- four hours, of the finding of the re- mains. The legs had been cut offclose to the trunk, the left one having been
              cut with a sharp knife, and the bone
              sawed through. The other leg was likewise cut, and the bone was partly
              sawed when it was broken off. • THEY WERE ENTIRELY NUDE.
              ; On the trunk were three shirts, the ' outer one being made of dark flannel.
              A leather strap was around the waist.
              The arms were not severed from the
              body, but were tied in front at the
              wrists with a stout cord. The head was crushed in horribly at the back, and
              there were three terrible knife wounds on the side of the face. The left jaw was also broken. The body is evidently that, of a German, about thirty-five
              years of age. Near the place where the
              bundles were placed was found a por- tion ofa newspaper, dated Dec. 5, the
              appearance of which indicated that it
              had been used for the purpose of wiping
              up blood. On the margin of the paper was written, in English, • the writing being evidently that of a German, the
              words: "Kohler Helab, Dooken hotel,"
              and right under ibis; -"Mrs.," repeated*
              several times. A portion of another
              | newspaper stained with blood was also
              ) found. There are wagon tracks all
              -.around the »pot, but the police are of
              the opinion that they ..were made by
              wagons hauling material used on the
              reservoir. The tracks, however, appear to have been made by a , wheelbarrow,
              and those investigating- the case are hopeful that this may furnish: a clue to aid them in unraveling a mystery which now ''\u25a0 y". '-' - SURROUNDS THE CRIME. V- )
              Last night a gardener-, living on the
              border of the park near where the re- mains were found was awakened by the
              furious barking of his dogs. . He seized
              his revolver and ran out doors. He saw an object moving from the direction of
              the park and hailed it. Receiving no
              reply, he attempted to fire his revofver, but the weapon would not go off. He
              went to the Reservoir hotel, situated at
              the Columbia avenue entrance to the
              park, aud told the proprietor, John
              Ernst, who went out into the darkness
              and saw a man walking from the direction of the reservoir. He called to the man to halt, but his command received no attention, and the mysterious visitor to the park disappeared in the darkness.
              The spot where the ghastly remains were found is a lonely one, and at this
              time of the year is seldom visited by
              any one, and the police therefore think
              the party orparties seen by Ernst and
              the gardener are connected with the
              crime which led to the placing of the
              cut-up body in the neglected portion of
              the park. The chief of detectives is
              working on the case, assisted by sev- eral of his best men, but the clues are slight.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90059522/1888-12-28/ed-1/seq-5/#words=Jack+Ripper</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              Jack the Ripper Sends Cold
              Chills Up the Eacks of
              Belgians. Jack, the Ripper, Throws the
              People ofBrussels Into a Spasm
              ofFear. , -. Special Cable to the Globe.
              Brussels, Dec. 27.—This city has
              been thrown into a ferment of excitement by the reception by prominent
              people of cards and telegrams announc- ing the advent in the quaint old city of
              the famous "Jack, the Kipper." of
              Whitcchapel notoriety. King Leopold,
              the prelect of police and the court ministers are amomr the recipients of this
              mysterious being's delicate attentions.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030272/1889-01-05/ed-1/seq-4//#words=Jack+Ripper</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              The Mania for Murder
              Tho English public aexcite by tho occurrence
              ¬
              of murders In parts of the
              kingdom which bear so strong a likeness
              those committed by JACK tho Ripper t they seem to b
              Imitations of lila horrible
              work A
              In Whltechapol Jurder the
              bodies the victims are mutiatd The
              kinseems to b
              dono a sher mania
              butchery none of the usual motives
              being discoverableIt Is not at all Impossible that JACK the
              Ripper has started a new school of murder
              and murderers Human experience shows that tho more morbid tho criminal manifestations
              ¬
              the more likely they ore to stlullt imitation
              breeds mania
              hi other
              or dlDnatur MI rther provokes It In minds
              dispse t
              insanity 0 set a whole hospital
              one
              ward
              hysterical
              of women-O
              to w-l
              screaming The notoriety of the Whit chapel murders brought them t
              tho atten ¬
              tion of that large number of persons whose
              mom Int1etuabncIs most likely
              upset nd among simple they have
              been the most engrossing subjectofthought
              and conversationThe conditions favorable t
              tho spread of
              a mania for Imitation terefor been
              present and the tat JACK
              the Ripper has not been caught punished
              ¬
              for his horrible crimes has undoubtedly
              a6lstein propagating a craze for killing
              own sake Even the Insane a
              deterred
              ¬
              from murder by dread of punishmentand fancied immunity from tho penalties
              visited on the criminal becomes t
              them
              Incentive to crime a
              Tho failure of the London police t
              bring
              tho Whlteohapel murderer to Justice s
              extraordinary
              ¬
              In the history of crime is there ¬
              fore I
              terrible social misfortune It Is making
              ¬
              of him a hero and an example Morbid
              minda
              likely to bo upset entirely by
              dwelling on his atrocities and his ability to
              commit them many times over without detection
              ¬
              Because ho Is Inhuman afiend In
              the form of a man ho excites devilish pro
              penalties uncontrollable In others except by
              the fear of certain punishmentIt is said by our police that oven hero In
              Now York there has been much tcrrornmong
              tho women of the street lest JACK tho Ripper
              should appear In person or stimulate others
              to engage In his horrible specialty The
              alarm of those women Is not surprising But In New York the career of such a
              would be short Because of that certainty
              so generally understood wo are not likely
              to havo Imitations of the Whltcchapol murders
              ¬
              though unless JACK the Ripper Is
              brought to Justice they are likely t
              our In England until he ceases t
              bo a
              subject of
              public discussion and curiosity
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn94052989/1890-10-25/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Jack+Ripper+body+dead+murder</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              "JACK THE RIPPER."
              Another Mysterious and Brutal Murder in London,
              Tlie Mutilated Body of a Woman DiscoVered in a Secluded Locality.
              Ealfour Staris on a Tour of Investigation
              Through the Western Counties
              oi Ireland.
              Special to The Morning Cam.
              London, Oct. 24.— The"Jaek-the-Ptipper"
              scare is on again to-uight. Ina secluded
              1 art ifthe South Ilampstead locality was
              found the dead body of a woman whose
              head had been nearly severed, while the
              l. dy showed kicks and bruises sufficient to
              cause death. The victim was a woman of
              low repute, and this was sufficient to start
              the cry of "Jack the Ripper."
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90059522/1891-04-25/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Jack+Ripper</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              IT'S JACK THERIPPER.
              The Notorious London Butcher Does a Regulation Job
              in New York City.
              A Dissolute Woman of the
              Slums Murdered inJack's
              Inimitable Lcj-ie.
              His Bloody Cross Is on the
              Base of the Spine of the
              Victim.
              The Police Have a Good Description of the Murderer
              to Work On.
              Netv York.April 24.—Now let the
              police of New York prove their boasted
              superiority over the police of London.
              Jack the Kipper is here. He has done
              his unspeakable work. His victim,
              mangied as he mangled her predecessors
              inthe grimlist in London, lies now as
              he left her inthe garret where the deed was done. Further than that, the
              weapon used has been found and is in
              the hands of the police. But. more than
              all. Jack the Ripper himself was
              seen before he did his bloody
              work The girl who saw him
              is able to give a close
              and clear description of him, and if
              brought face to face with him can identifyhim positively. The story of the
              crime is horrible in its simplicity and in
              its familiarity. Under different sur- roundings, and withmodifications incident to those surrounninsrs. it is an
              exact repetition of the horrible atrocities of Whitechapel. The scene is in a
              little dirty squalid room up on the fourth
              aiid topmost rioor of a wretched lodging
              house, known as the East River house,
              and kept by one James Jennings.
              The house is at the corner of Water and Catharine streets and is designated as 16Catharine
              Slip. The entrance proper is on Water
              street. The door here opens into a
              short hallway. At the end of this pass- age a flight of narrow, worn wooden
              stairs goes up to the tioor above. Here a book is kept called a register, and in
              this register Edward Fitzgerald, the
              clerk of the house, writes such names as persons seeking rooms for the uisrht
              choose to give him. Through this
              Water street doorway and up the flight
              ofstairs there came, at10:45 last night
              two persons. One was a woman who
              could not have been much under
              Sixty Years ofAge.
              Her hair had passed the iron gray stage and was almost white. Her feat- area were small, irregular and stamped with the mark of drunkenness and the
              gutter. She wore an old black skirt and waist, and on her head was riunr a shawi. Bfee was a cynical specimen oi
              the drunken old harridan of the slums.
              Her companion, the man whom the en- tire police force of New Fork is now bending its energies to capture, was the opposite in nearly every respect to the woman. In point of years he might have been her son. "
              He was not a day.to all appearances,over thirty- one or thirty-two years of litre. Inbuild
              he was slisht. and he was not over live
              feet eight inches in height He had a light complexion, a small blond mus- tache and blond hair. The woman. when she came in, was in a cheerful
              .md apparently under alcoholic
              influence. She laughed at the very
              tirst. and asked her companion to buy her beer. To this he made no reply,bin
              handed a 10-cent piece over to the worn- j an without a single word. She asked
              him if she might get the beer,
              and he simply nodded his
              ClerkFitzgerald asked them what name j he should put upon the register. To
              this the man replied withwhat sounded to the clerk like C. Knicio, and so he i wrote itupon the hotel register. Inall probability the stranger endeavored to give tiie German name Nicolal—C. Nicolai. Whether or not tliat is his real name remains to be seen. That the
              horrible butcher deliberately set out to tind a victimseems beyond question, just as itis apparently equally sure that the only motive forthe deed was sheer brute
              thirst ror blood and horrible mutilation.
              Atall events, with a sputtering candle I
              inhis hand, be led the way up three nights of stairs above the tioor where
              the so-calied office is kept and reached i
              the fourth or top floor ofthe house. The room assigned to him was No. 31. It is
              the coiner room and. like all the other rooms of the house, it was a mere Style ola Hole.
              On a narrow bed next the partition wall was a erimy. greasy mattress and
              pillowand a few wretched bed clothes.
              There was one old wooden chair in the
              room, and a dirty, rickety little washstand. Into this little den. which was soon to be turned into so horrible a slaughter-pen, the gray-headed, halfdrunken woman and the young palefaced man were siiown. The price demanded for the accommodation was 50 cents. The man paid it and said nothing. Not a soul in the house
              heard him speak. At 10 o'clock this morning a boy whose duty it is to rouse the tardy lodgers, pushed open the door ofNo. 31. and there beheld such a scene of horror as he will not forget to his dying day. Stretched out on the bed,naked from the waist down,lyingon her rizht side, with botli arms twisted
              and bent under her, her head enveloped in fold after foldof cloth,the old woman lay stark dead on a mattress soaked
              with her blood. She had been com- pletely disemboweled, and the terrible
              result of the operatiou was drawn out and scattered over the
              entire lower part of the bed.
              The boy. after one glance at this ap- pallingspectacle, flew away and gave the alarm. Police Capt. O'Connor "and
              two roundsmen made a careful search
              of the room, and on the floor close by the bed. with its haft and blade still wet withblood, lay the knife withwhich
              the deed was done. Itwas a cheap, or- dinary table knife, with its olade
              broken diagonally off about half its length and ground down to a sharp edge
              and point. This and a small cloth reticule ingay colors Capt. O'Connor car- ried to the station house. Coroner Shultz, at 2 o'clock, went to the room of the tragedy. The body lay precisely | as it had been found. The coroner shoved itirently over on its rightaide, revealing fully
              The AwfulNature
              of the mutilation. The cut extended
              from the middle of the abdomen down
              through the length of the abdominal cavity. The entrails were scattered over the lower portion of the
              bed. Itlooked as though they had been furiously dragged out in a wild frenzy of blood. Whether any of the parts are missing, as was the case with the London murders, has not yet been fuily
              ascertained. The woman was either
              stone dead or insensible at the time the
              mutilation was inHicted. She had
              been strangled to death. Tightly knotted about ier throat, so that it left two red welta when removed, was a portion of tha wretched creature's chemise. The knota were tied so tight that the coroner had to cut them to get them loose. Over this and about the head was found a portion of a sheet, and over this still was tied the woman's own blue checked
              apron. When thu coverings were re\ moved ttie face was seen to be turned slightly upward. The eyes were tightly closed. The expression on tha face was one ofagony. The old wom- an, slight and weak as she was. had evidently strangled hard. Her gray hair was allundone, and hung in tangleY about her ghastly tace. The deed must have been well niirh noiseless. Tne ad joiningroom is only separated by a thin board partition. It would be*almost possible to hear a whisper through it, let the man who slept there heard not a sound. The assassin did his work; stole quietly away, and Jack the Kirjper s
              First Bloody Mark
              had been made inNew I'ork. Nobody had heard the man leave during the night or morning. He might do itwith- out disturbing anybody, as the front door unlocks easily from the inside. The murderer, when he had done his foul work, locked the door as he went*
              out and carried the key away, with its tag 31 attached. Anexamination of tha registry book showed that almost
              every room on the top floor where the couple slept had been occupied oven night. The witness described the man as wearins a brown coat, a turn- down collar and a derby hat. A doctor who saw the body before it was removed says: "Whether by chance orskill the cut was made so a'a to effect the object aimed at by the Lon- don Jack the Ripper, namely, the re*' moval of the uterus. The incision was begun near the termination ot the back- bone, and carried from below upward1
              inan oblique direction, to a point halt
              way up on the right side of the ab- domen. Then, apparently, the knife was carried around the perLnaeum,butch- er-fashion, and the uterus, rectum and) bladder pulled out together. The bladder,
              is stilllyingon the bed carefully sepa-j rated from its -surrounding attachments., The rectum has likewise been divided:
              offfrom adjacent structures, and a su-i perficial examination did not tind thoi uterus, although it may stili be Lying] underneath the corpse. "One thing is certain, the uterus must have been in: the murderer's hands whether he knew; itor not. for the presence of the other:
              structures without it proves that it! must have been withdrawn from' the body. The resemblance be-'
              tween this murder and those credited to Jack the Kipper in London is thus strong enough to warrant the pre-! sumption that the obiect aimed at was the same, although the procedure was sliehtly different." inspector Williams ;
              is to-night assisting Inspector Byrnes in,
              questioning the people continually' being brought in by the largest force of central . otliee detectives
              and policemen ever at work on a single case' in New York. One ofi
              the women arrested, a Mrs.Harrington,' who keeps a lodging house, gave in- formation whereby the police arrested a man known inhis haunts aa "Frenehy," . and who, according toMrs. Harrington, was an acquaintance of the dead
              woman, whose name she said was Carrie Brown, wn. sixty years
              years old.
              olu. The woman
              woman formerly lived out at service, but was so much given to riotous livingthat she ac- quired an unenviable reputation and
              thus lost her- chances of gaininir an honest livelihood. The police Would give no information concerning the man,, nor wouldthey give his right name. At 1 o'clock this morning a man by the name of Adoiph Kellenberg was af-'
              rested. Ili-s description answers that of
              the murderer.
              (would they give Ins right name.
              /
              ocfc this morning a man by name of Adoiph Kellenberg w 3d. His description answers that of
              murderer
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030272/1891-04-25/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Jack+Ripper</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              JACK THE RIPPERS MARK
              TllK rOVnOY CRIMES ISItTATKO Itf A
              WATER STHIUtT ATI
              After Butchering cmi Old hug ol tkeNtreta
              the Murderer tteratehe a Cross Vpoa f
              tier Bodr He was Ooaa Hoar Befbr
              the Body wit Foandni IVeel Known
              Thoachnnd the New York route have
              Thnl Advnntnit Over Heotland Yard
              lie Lets ntu Knllv Too and Onrrird
              Away tkn Key of the XoomA Bad KMKnonm as frcneby Aniona TkoM
              Vader An tA Drag 2511 Cnat IK the
              Low Kecorl Inapeetor Byrces Tka
              the Field In ParaonBnntlnc In Prteaers CroavaxnBlnatlon
              The painted bags who swarm on the rlvar
              front between Itoosevelt and Catharine streets
              havelost ono of their number An Imitator
              Jack the flipper It not Jack himself butcharad
              her on Thursday night and escaped at hl
              leisure leaving her mutilated remains in the
              wretched room hey had taken for tbenUtht
              Last night a large force of police wore drat
              glng the low resorts ot the neighborhood tad
              Inspectors flumes and Williams were attha
              station house aquentlonlng the prisoner
              They had found out who the murdered womaa
              r
              1
              1
              4-
              I
              THE uuBcsnttti rooKKD BoucrniNO LIvE ran
              thIs plotvr U drawn from UurlllBluriiluutpUoa
              otthmca1
              wits and hal arrested several men among
              them one who It la said WAS teen with her
              early on Thursday evening 4
              Ills victim was a grayheaded drunkard who
              joined the Water street sisterhood several
              months ago Who she was or where she asme
              from nobody seemed to know and nobody
              oared until she was murdered In her cup she
              talked enough to mnke It clearthat sba gravitated
              ¬
              naturally toward the river liar husband
              she said had been seafaring man She made
              herself at home in the slums anti was a talkative
              ¬
              companion when drinks wore solar She
              THl OLD VICTIM 41
              and two women known aa Mamlo Healey mad
              Lizzie were wont to lurk about the dirty seat
              side street at all hours of the night in search
              of their prey the eallorman Mamie Healer
              never learned what the graybeaded woman1
              name wee but somebody one dar called her
              Shakespeare The name stuck her and
              she responded to It
              The Host Biter Hotel on tha aontheast eon
              ner of Catharine and Water streets tsaflve
              story brick building that presents a clean end
              solid front to the street but the interior la
              rickety and dirty A squat blockwbUkered
              man named ames Jennings keeps the place
              Itis an assignation house of the lowest order
              The corner of the first floor is taken up by a
              liquor store that can be entered from both
              streets On the Water street side there are
              two other entrances The one neareut Catharine
              ¬
              street IB shrouded by a bUr square storm
              house that has doors on both ends This U
              called the family entrance and loads Into a
              little square room In which are a few chair
              and a big sign that notifies customers that the
              proprietor will not be responsible for anything
              that happens to them ifthey fall asleep timers
              Opposite the entrance dnor Is a door opening
              on a narrow passage which takes you to the
              barroom if you turn to the left and to the
              stairs It you turn to the right Near the west
              end of the building on Water street is another
              door that comes out flush with tho street and
              is unprotected by any awning or porch In
              tile centre panel ot this door near the top la
              an electric belL
              A little alter 9 oclock on Thursday night the
              old woman went Into the liquor store by way
              of the family entrance Mary Healey waa with
              her and the two women pal In the private rooai
              and drank some beer They had both reached
              HODSB WHXXI na Huron wia HOPS
              the garrulous stage of IntoxleatloUlnlter
              Wuy
              who Is an assistant to Mary Cody t
              housekeeper spoke to the two wretched g
              creatures and finally began chatting wt
              them They spoke of the troubles that wall
              life of toll manually Shakespeare sal
              83ft1 HlnltarAh my dear if you bad known all the trou ¬
              Lie I Ti aT you would not be alive pow
              Mary Hlnltar sighed In sympathy with her
              and thus encouraged the old woman went on My father waa a sea apuujn and he waa
              drowned nn the Pacific coast I used to live
              then nd I married my husband there Just
              think I hal
              two daughters The oldestot them
              lsaityears
              The old woman ohatte away cpuS said a Rood
              many more tbingepu MaryMlulter paid little
              attention because she Is used to hearing then
              wretches talk of better days About 10 oclock
              the two old Women left the place
              TUB XDRDBBCB DOME IX WITH flUKBaPKAXrAa nearly as the tIme could ba fixed yester ¬
              day It was bout U oclock when the woman
              known M Shakespeare rang the electric bell
              on the door loading Into the hotel Eddy PIta
              gerald W years cm usually answers this bell
              put the bartender Ham Shine was busy play ¬
              hill cards with a customer la the barroom and
              Eddy was behind the liar Bo Mary MlnlVr
              opened the door sad Shakaioeare came In
              with the man that the entire police and detective
              ¬
              force ot this city were looking fur yestar
              liPit
              the left side of the hallway pear the
              there It anleh in the wall intended
              rntrancaaatatue In this the register of tna 5 hotel usually yeet but when Kddy Vltc
              gerald wept 10 tha barroom be carrIed tie
              book with Elm The hall is dimly U btad with
              Inslajet that hangs near the eelllnx nndbedi non huowi tbta licbt Mi
              sos
              U l
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn94056415/1891-05-01/ed-1/seq-6/#words=Jack+Ripper</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              He
              .
              Fa e Away In His Ninety-first
              Year of Heart Disease Jack the
              Ripper Ucllcv.ed to Have Taken Up
              Residence In New York His First
              Victim In that City The Lottery
              Companies Receive a Black 'ByePork to Boom Immigration Hum ¬
              bert's Angry Subjects. 
              Jack the Ripper In America.-
              NEAV
              .
              YOKK , April 25 "Jack the
              Ripper, " is believed by the police to
              have at last come to this city. Yesterday
              ¬
              morning in the East River ho ¬
              tel the body of a wretched woman was
              found with her abdomen horribly cut
              and her bowels protruding. Her name
              is not known. The resort in which
              the body was found is one of the lowest
              ¬
              in the city. It is located on the
              southeast corner of Catherine and Market
              ¬
              streets. The woman was known
              about the neighborhood as one of the
              half drunken creatures who hang about
              the low resorts of Water street and
              Riverside. She came to the hotel last
              night in company with a man who reg ¬
              istered as Knickloi and wife. The
              couple were assigned to a room on the
              upper floor and went to it at once.
              Nothing was seen or heard of them
              during the night. 'No cry or unusual
              noise was heard. This morning the
              attendant rapped at the door of the
              room occupied by the couple. There
              was no answer and he rapped again
              with no better result and finally broke
              in the door. A horrible sight met his
              gaze. On the bed lay the woman in a
              big pool of blood. She had been dead
              for hours. Her abdomen had been
              fairly ripped open with a dull, broken
              table knife that lay in the pool of blood.
              The viscera had been cut, and from
              appearances a part was missing. The
              woman's head was bandaged. A cloth
              had been tied about her neck and face ,
              but whether for any foul purpose or to
              hide any other traces of murder the
              attendant did not wait to see.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1963-03-31/ed-1/seq-232/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20&words=Jack+Ripper&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=jack+the+ripper&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              London’s Jack the Ripper never was
              caught after his 10 murders between
              1888 and 1891. The popular theory is
              that he was an insane physician.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn96060044/1960-12-19/ed-1/seq-12/#date1=1756&index=1&rows=20&words=JACK+RIPPER&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=jack+the+ripper&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1915-05-11/ed-1/seq-2/#date1=1756&index=3&rows=20&words=JACK+Jack+Ripper+RIPPER&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=jack+the+ripper&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              JACK THE RIPPER" HAS NEW
              YORK IN TERROR
              New York, May 11. "Jack the
              Ripper" who slew Leonore
              Conn, March 29, and Charlie Murray, a week ago has New
              York's East Side in a state of terror.
              Warnings believed to have come from
              this supposed madman that he intends slashing to death more children
              have caused mothers throughout the
              tenement districts to keep their little ones off the streets.
              The "ripper's" warnings that he intended to commit more murders were
              contained in letters to the mothers
              of his two victims.
              New York. After robbing Giovanni Sarcona of $100, two robbers yelled "Jack the Ripper." Crowd--
              that
              gathered was bent on lynching Sarcona when police reserves arrived
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1960-02-14/ed-1/seq-130/#date1=1756&index=9&rows=20&words=JACK+Jack+Ripper+RIPPER&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=jack+the+ripper&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              HE FILE ON JACK THE RIPPER
              HAS NEVER BEEN CLOSED!
              Identity Os Infamous Slasher
              Still Bewilders Crime Analysts A storm of controversy is raging One of the major theories concernover one of the most diabolical fig- ing the killer is that he was a medures in the annals of crime, Jack ical student who became maddened
              The Ripper. In his violent lifetime against "ladies of the night” for
              he killed at least six and possibly some personal reason. "The Rip- *¦
              as many as a dozen women, eluding per” proved so clever and elusive
              police dragnets even as he struck that even the celebrated Arthur
              down women in the heart of “spe- Conan Doyle, together with Scotcially protected” areas of the city. land Yard, was baffled by his
              .. ,
              identity. The Ripper , whose case was
              marked "Unsolved” and placed in There is great advance excitement
              the “Still Active” files of the po- about the motion picture. “Jack
              lice, has been alternately consid- The Ripper” suggests a startling
              ered to be a prominent doctor, a solution to the identity of the
              madman, a foreign spy, an artist, super-criminal who has Scotland
              a religious maniac, an embittered Yard, and the world, guessing to
              former policeman and even an en- this day. ——
              raged husband who took out his
              frustrations toward his . RVIWF
              wife on other
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn96060044/1962-12-17/ed-1/seq-12/#date1=1756&index=5&rows=20&words=JACK+RIPPER&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=jack+the+ripper&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1915-09-30/ed-1/seq-9/#date1=1756&index=15&rows=20&words=Jack+Ripper&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=jack+the+ripper&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1961-04-30/ed-1/seq-187/#date1=1756&index=16&rows=20&words=Jack+Ripper&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=jack+the+ripper&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88063294/1944-10-01/ed-1/seq-66/#date1=1756&index=18&rows=20&words=Jack+Ripper&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=jack+the+ripper&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84024720/1911-11-24/ed-1/seq-2/#date1=1756&sort=relevance&rows=20&words=Jack+Jack%7Ethe-Ripper+Ripper&searchType=basic&sequence=0&index=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=jack+the+ripper&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=2</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              Thirteenth Victim is Claimed
              By Atlanta's "Jack~the-Ripper"
              —He Murders One Every Week
              Strange Series of Crimes Completely Baffles Army of Detectives-
              People in State of Terror
              several months by some unknown
              "Jack, the Ripper," the murderer
              avenging a victim a week. In each
              case th e bodies have been found hor
              ribly mutilated, the fiend using some
              sharp instrument, presumably a raz
              or. While these crimes have been
              committed with startling regularity,
              the murderer almost invariably
              choosing Saturday as th e day for
              his deeds, and while the entire pop
              ulation of Atlanta has been kept in
              a state bordering on terror, the po
              lice so far have been unable to find
              a single definite clue that would
              lead to the capture of the "ripper."
              The following account of th e thir
              teenth murder is taken from the
              Her throat cut from ear to ear,
              her heart cut out and lying by her
              side, and otherwise terribly mutilat
              ed, the remains of an unknown ne
              gro woman were found Tuesday
              morning buried in the side of an em
              bankment on the West Point belt
              line, 100 yards to the right of Stew
              art avenue—The thirteenth victim
              of the mysterious and elusive Jack
              The Ripper—the second within a
              This latest victim was more horri
              bly mutilated than any of the others
              in the ripper's long list of unsolved
              and bloody crimes. Not only did
              the murderer cut the woman's head
              almost off and remove her heart,
              but he knocked out her teeth and
              disemboweled her. This was done
              with two long slashes with his knife
              or razor. One gash extended down
              ward, the full length of the trunk,
              from the throat down over the abdo
              men. The other gash extended
              across the abdomen, from side to
              side-—the two gashes being at right
              Completing his fiendish act, the
              murderer dragged the remains down
              the embankment, about midway,
              where he dumped them into a gully
              and buried them. First covering
              the remains with several old flour
              sacks, he then pulled soft earth into
              the gulley with his hands.
              Children Make Discovery.
              The murder was discovered by
              two negro children, who, while pick
              ing up coal along the railroad em
              bankment, found the murdered wo
              man's comb and a trail of blood.
              Running to their home, the children
              informed their mother of their find,
              and she at once visited the scene, dis
              covering the improvised grave. The
              police were then immediately noti
              fied, and Captain Mayo, of the morn-
              $100 REWARD $100
              In Good American U. S. Gold
              If any miller who makes the so
              called "new patent process high
              grade wheat Hour, buckwheat and
              cornmeal" ground by steel rolls; if
              he can show that the Electro Mag
              netic Sifter, the invention of Dr.
              Thos. T. Fauntleroy, (Inventor and
              Patentor) does not remove the par
              ticles of steel —the wear and tear of
              the steel rolls to best grind the flour
              and also all such as nails, screws,
              tacks and short end wires which are
              contantly slipping through the clean
              ers and form by their mechanical
              cutting caused by the peralstalic of
              the bowels, and vereformis, appendi
              citis and ulceration and constriction
              of the bowels.
              This sifter renders the flour so
              made a pure food product and is
              called "Steel Eliminated Flour."
              The inventor offers this reward and
              ask your grocer for the "Steel Elimi
              nated Flour" and if he cannot furn
              ish it drop Mr. E. A. Hammer of Mc-
              Dowell, Va., a postal—he makes it
              and can furnish you it at the same
              price you are paying for that which
              is mixed with steel particles.
              ...
              When the remains were removed j
              from i!he embankment they were
              still warm, indicating that th e mur
              der had been committed but a short
              time before. The murderer had
              carefully placed the woman's heart
              by her side before covering the
              reihains.
              Dogs Lose the Trail.
              The police at once obtained County
              mnian Shockley's bloodhounds
              ok them to the grave in the
              embankment. The dogs quickly
              struck a scent and trailed it a dis
              tance of 200 yards to the Stewart
              avenue trolley line. There the trail
              was lost. This fact convinces the
              I that the murderer boarded an
              ng Stewart avenue car, prob
              he first car on the morning
              This is the only clew to the
              rer so far unearthed.
              s that Jack th e Ripper had
              d another victim spread like
              re in that section and created
              intense excitement among the ne
              groes. It was but a short time until
              I sited crowd of curious specta
              ,ere r on the scene.
              His Twelfth Victim.
              twelfth victim was found a
              ago in the lowlands just off
              y street, and but a short dis
              south of Georgia avenue. This
              i's throat was cut from ear
              her head was crushed in and
              dcx ftager on her right hand
              evered at the middle joint,
              crime was similar to several
              1 others, in that the victim's
              were removed and carried
              In the murder of Tuesday
              ng the woman's shoes wer e not
              cd.
              sral theories are advanced by
              lice as to the fiendish murder
              it the prevailing opinion is
              ie is a fanatic of som c kind,
              agent of some organized so-
              The police believe that if
              sver captured he will prove to
              riminal far above the average
              icity and will be an interesting
              ± am satisfied this murderer is a
              fanatic, incited to murder through
              some weird belief," is the theory of
              Captain Mayo, expressed just after
              he had viewed the mutilated remains
              of the latest victim Tuesday morning.
              Captain Poole, of the day watch,
              who went on duty at 8 o'clock, had
              a conference with Captain Mayo and
              Chief Beavers and is aiding in the
              investigation.
              The murder was committed in an
              isolated section the nearest house
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1915-03-20/ed-2/seq-3/#date1=1756&sort=relevance&rows=20&words=Jack+Ripper&searchType=basic&sequence=0&index=5&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=jack+the+ripper&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=2</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-harry-houdini/selected-articles</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1906-01-07/ed-1/seq-43/#words=King+Handcuff+Houdini</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              6
              THE WA VASHINGTON aurNrTON JIMES4 IiRiTiF4 SUNDAY SiVtIA V JANUARY TA hTTARY 7 7 1906 7
              l
              q 1
              IGKING I ING my m lway way nervously nervouslythrough n flprvouslyI rou5IY rou5IYthroU1Ch
              I through a group of man manacleladen nlanaol nianaclyladen ¬
              P
              acleladen aol IAden detective last lastTuesday lastTuOlldAY lastTuoeday
              Tuesday owning oenin I reach reachmi reached reached
              ed the back of Chases Chasesstage ChasQsJitas bases basesstage
              stage and and accosted Mr Harry Houdin1 Hou Houdinl Houdini
              dinl tha Handcuff King to whom whomI
              I disclosed my identity and men mentioned mentioned mentioned ¬
              tioned my opinion of his Iia stuntWm stunt atuntWhen stuntVllen
              When can we ge together for fora fora fora
              a wordiest wordfestr wordfe t r I Inquired InquiredRight IntulrodRtcllt inaluirodRight
              Right now If you like h he ro ropiied 10IJlied replied
              plied with an energetic manner manndrthat mfinnortbat mannerthat
              that aroused my admiration admirationTomorrow admirationTomorrow admirationTomorrow
              Tomorrow morales mornl1 will do I Ihedged Ihed Ihedged
              hedged hed If you can make mak it early earlyenough fMlrlyenouch oarlyenough
              enough enoughI
              hI I uhi usually my sleep until
              wventhir wventhirty IiEtVQnthht vQ114IIiI vQ114IIiIty
              ty t he 11 said apalovM apol0 apolOeUoally gnlly but b t ifoar if ifyou iflOll
              you oar want to gee 0 me m earlier than ihanthat thanI thanthat
              I 1that
              that
              Heaven forbid I interrupted interruptedAuth Interruptedit
              Auth it ith h a shiver Let us compromise compromiseon
              on o on eloy elereji t And All we did didAt didAt didAt
              At the Regent next ext morning maraln I Ifound Itounel Ifound
              found feint 11 with his wife wtG who is Iris lUsstage l Irisstage s sstage
              stage partner and their diminutive diminutivepet diminutivepet diminutivepet
              pet dog d who as Mr Mrs Houdini ex explained exlained axplained ¬
              plained lained plaintively seems ll ems to be the theonly thponly theonly
              only liriats ltYi creature that does do tl not notinsist noti notinsist
              insist i nsi upon bringing maaaclos to tohind toind tobind
              hind ind h her r husbands hi limbs JIm It struck stmekme struckme struckme
              me that I had a lookin on the dogsrating dogs dogsrating dOSsIatl
              rating Iatl rating but I did not urge ur the point pointYon J pointYou > Olnt OlntYou
              You Impressed the t e deteethv detectives det etl1tl8 a very verymuck verrmuch very verymuch
              much test alght I told Houdini UI UIheanl I Iheard Iheard
              heard one 08 of them declare most em ant1hat emphatically QmJhatJeaUy ¬
              phatically 1hat call that you were on the thedead Utedead thedead
              dead fcreL fcreLThe level levelThe JJ JJThe
              The battdeulfc 1fJI they Ule triad OH me mewere m mwere matwere
              were ilagy a he to rlisdEvIdsatly replted reptsdEyffttl repltedErid
              EvIdsatly Erid Eyffttl tly the stationhowee statlon1totls ia iawhich illwhich Inwhich
              which they locked you QI up tp was wasequally wasquaIl wasequally
              equally < < quaIl easy y I said admiringly Idftlrfn atMi Ingly I Ishould Ifohoult Ishonld
              should like Uk to know Kll W how you get getout getout et etOil
              out Oil t It night be useful Informa InformaI InforIftftiCln iiforntamn
              iCln
              I took > a ti tone chance CHHello there he heKii hetdd hea
              tdd Kii a + id < l aitd 1 d tw there was a noUoenUie noUeenhIetinge Jtotlae1tltinge noUoenUietinge
              tinge otUttenlels of UtteriMSB Jtter1Ml in kit klaYGI reline yoieeHow relineHow e eHow
              How was tHatr tHatrThey t1aaUTJaey that thatThey
              They They didnt xt Etve gif me a SQuars SQuarsdeal s4ttA s4ttAutal sit 1Rre 1Rredeal
              deal lie xlptitld replied I Iwnl went to tothom thorn
              lice at the precinct to which they theytook theytook theytook
              took me agreed to this thlsbut but after aftertho afterthe afterthe
              the test was startea I heard him himwhisper himwhisper himwhisper
              whisper to one of ins ts men to bring bringhim bringhim bringhim
              him the locks for another cell cellNaturally cellNaturally cellNaturally
              Naturally I objected to any anychange anychange anychange
              change and he became bcc me most offen offensive offensive offensive ¬
              sive in his manner He told me mehis mehis mehis
              his orders were to lock me up and andkeep andIUHlP andheap
              keep me there and intimated that thatif thatIf thatit
              if I was afraid I could pass the thing thingup thingup thingup
              up and take the consequences I re remonstrated remonstrated remonstrated ¬
              monstrated with him and told him himto himto himto
              to remember that I was not a criminal crim criminal crI crIinaI ¬
              inal That I had come to him of ofmy otm ofmy
              my m own accord and deserved the thecourtesy thecourtosy thecourtesy
              courtesy due an equal Bu Butihe he could couldnot couldnot couldnot
              not see SO it and continued his brutal brutalthreatening brutalthreatening brutalthreatening
              threatening attitude attitudeThen attitudeThen attitudeThen
              Then I lost my head and went wontahead wentahead wentahead
              ahead recklessly I know now that thatI
              I was foolish to do so for
              my imp imputation rarutation qp qputaHon ¬
              utation Is well established In ov overy overy every
              ery large city In Un world and I didnot did didnot didnot
              not need the Washington test Of Ofcourse orcourse Ofcourse
              course I was endangering my reputation rep reputation reputation ¬
              utation in submitting to a change changeof changeof changeof
              of lodes for if they had got me by byany bJrany byany
              any means whatever my standing standingwould standingwould standingwould
              would have been een badly damaged damagedBut damagedBut damagedBut
              But you got out outYes outYos outYou
              Yes I got out in eighteen mn mnutes min minutes minutes ¬
              utes to the great surprise of the thelieutenant theJioutonant thelloutonant
              lieutenant He had evidently been beenprepared beenprepared beenprepared
              prepared to bet anything that I Icouldnt Icouldnt Icouldnt
              couldnt do It It Why Vhy he would have havestaked havestaked havestaked
              staked his head on keeping me inNot in inNot inNot
              Not that that article is of any val value value al alH ¬
              ue H added Houdini sarcastically sarcasticallyI
              I am sorry to hear Washington Washingtontreated WashingtontrOtlted Washingtontreated
              treated you unfairly tm lilrly I said Haveany Haveapy Have Hateally
              any other police departments show showed showed showed ¬
              ed the same attitude attitudeNot attitudeNot attitudeNot °
              Not one he replied with em emphasis ompltasis emphasis ¬
              phasis I have broken out of Scot Scotland Scotland Scotland ¬
              land Yard in London and escaped escapedfrom oscapodfrom escapedfrom
              from the police of Dresden Berlin BerlinGologneParIs BerlinCologne BerlinCologneParls
              GologneParIs Cologne Paris and dozens of other otherEuropean otherEuropean otherEuropean
              European cities I was locked in inthe Inth6 Inthe
              the Moscow Siberian transportation transportationcoll transporta transportationtoll on oncoB
              coB and examined beforehand by the thehardened thelUirdonod thehardened
              hardened Russian secret police of official ofnetal ofilcials ¬
              ficial But though they all made
              1t 1tI
              I
              I
              t
              a
              i
              3 1 1a
              a
              I
              4 9 9n 9Examined
              t
              11
              s 1s 1
              t
              n
              0 0Exaj11
              Exaj11 Examined Ae or1t oriticallY cally the imposing stack of police admissions admissionsto t
              to defeat at the hands of Houdini
              and as I always do in tae citia cities I Ivisit IisH Iti
              visit ti isH offered them the chance to tolock tolock tolock
              lock me ti Iii and keep me there if ifthey itt f fthey
              they t hey could But I made mnd the condi condition condilion ndi ndition ¬
              tion I always insist on that I should shouldee shouldsee
              see ee the cell in which they intended intaudedplacing intendedplacing intonQllacin
              placing me m and an examine the locks locksto loeksto locksto
              to be urea The lieutenant of po
              the tost as severe as possible they theyall the theyxll t tin
              all gave me an absolutely square squaredeal squaredeal
              deal and accorded mo themost the most cour courteous 1 1toous
              toous treatment Since my return returnto
              to the United States I have broken brokenout 1 1out
              out of stationhouses in New York YorkBrooklyn YorlcBrooldyn YorkBrooklyn
              Brooklyn Rochester Buffalo De Detroit Detroit
              troit troit and and Baltimore but it has re
              mained for Washington to treat me meJfke meJfke molike
              like a common c ontnio n m malefactor malefactorI alefactorI
              I gather that you are not favor favorably fa or orably orably
              ably impressed by the Capital po poHce police
              lice I observedTile observed observedThe observedThe
              The fact that my wife is isPrevents present presentprevents presentprevents
              prevents me from telling you ex exactly exactly
              actly what I do think of o f that lieu lieutonant lIeutonant lieutenant
              tenant and his assistants herepJi herepJicd
              cd You can probably guess what whatI
              I would say if she were not in the theTen theTen
              Ten me somethIng some hing about your yourself yourself yoursoli
              self I s suggested gested How did you ou oubreak oubreak
              break into vaudovUle vaudovUleI
              I started in the t he fjh she ho w = b business
              I Iwas was a youngster but my myuother mynother
              took mo out anti ant apprenticed apprenticedtie apI > lcnUccd lcnUccdne
              tie to a locksmith That is where wheregot wheregot
              got my first knowledge of the theveakness theveakness
              1ptknl > Q of nf locks Tn1r I T J
              discovered a anethod anethod
              of opening them which I Icept Iecpt
              to myself One day the sheriff
              the town brought in a prisoner p1lsonerlandcufted pi isoaer
              and asked my employer
              remove r move the manacles as the key keylad
              been broken roken I was told to file filehem
              off and set to work worlc The Theherifi
              and my employer eD1pIo er went out outo outo
              o get a drink and left me at work workh
              h steel was very tough and I Imde
              practically pr8cticall no progress at the he heIng
              Ing Then it occurred to me to topen
              pen the lock by means means of my secret secretIrocEss
              I did so without difficulty difficultylut
              in doingso doing so of course COtl course I gaVe gt ve the theecret
              away to the prisoner He Is ishe
              only person In the wori wori1 < 1 uoside lJOsldeny
              wife who knows how I opeii opeicks
              cks and I have never heard from from11m
              11m since I became tired of the theDoksmlth
              business and ran away awaylith
              lith a circus One of my tricksz tricks trlclreVag
              Vag escaping from from z ropes rop ropes s that had hadEt1n hadeen
              Et1n bound around nr und my arms arms Oh O 1
              r
              one occasion a sheriff in the uuili uuilionce utUlionce atidionce
              once told me that if ha put his hishandcuffs hishandcuffs hishandcuffs
              handcuffs on m me I couldnt getaway get getaway gotaway
              away I took too a look at them and anddecided anddecided anddecided
              decided I could He locked them on onand onand on onand
              and in twenty minutes I was free freeThat freeThat freeThat
              That started me in the line I now nowfollov nowfoHm nowfollotir
              follov follotirWhy >
              Why did dl you TQU go b go abroad abroadTo abroad abroadTo abroadTo
              To giA gt a reputation I I tried to toget t tget toget
              get into vaudeville audevm here but I Jcouldnt Zcouldnt Icouldnt
              couldnt make it go g I Iwas was was practi practically praoti praotically practically ¬
              cally starving starvingliving living in garrets garretswhile garrotswhile garretswhile
              while traveling around giving gi ing ax axhibitions o ohi6iUons axhiliitions
              hibitions I offered to give giv the ex exhibition exhibiUon axhibition ¬
              hibition on the vaudeville circuit for
              40 a week but I was turned turned down downNow downF downf
              F
              Now I get a thousand I saw I had hadno hadno hadno
              no chance In this country so I Iscraped 1scraped Iscraped
              scraped up a little money and took tooka tooka
              a chance at London Manager Slaterof Slater Slaterof Slater Slaterof
              of the London vaudeville housegave house housegave housegave
              gave me several private trials and nd
              l
              00 D
              LLiLLiLM LLiLLiLMmained Lffl
              lHce
              y
              r ractlY
              DLLiLLiLM
              l A
              i
              w
              fjhIhon bt
              t 2 d 4
              i
              1
              5 11lUG Is some literature you might
              1 I 5 1 1
              5 5 1 1 r like to take along alon he said produc producr
              r lug a collection of pamphlets cover covering covering
              i ii ing hie hi dom doings In for foreign isn lands Jand as aswell
              i 1
              4 well as th the story of hta life from fromtho fromiI
              °
              tho time iI or his birth April G 1873 1873In
              1 f In Appleton WiL to the pre present presentday cnt cntday
              1 T2 day We shook band cordially awl awlHoudtnf
              Houdtnf acoompanlecl me Ins down the tarehall thehalIto
              halIto hall to show m methe the proper lltalraf atairwari
              i 7
              I suppos suppose If I f I sat t et Jockad oa ked In any anyot an Y Yo
              1 t L1s7 1 1tf ot o ltes thooo b e rooms r ml you y 0u wmdcl get IDe IDeOttt
              fl Ottt r I called baalt 1Nl to hlI hlIsona Uiso
              Send fOr me an7 tIme you get getljj
              l r
              f
              v
              11 11rr
              rr rri
              i tl rrl rrlI
              I ii
              f I ryr 1
              i
              1
              +
              1 1IfJfIJ
              IfJfIJ I g 1 iir 1
              7 f lk
              F41 I ljj ljjtJ71J1
              E
              tJ71J1 tJ71J1I
              dr I C tI f1k
              I E0 6
              t d
              Found him with his Vie who whois whois
              y t is his stage partner partnerIhon
              f
              locked up he answered user with a alauh a another aaUlh alaugh
              laugh lauhIn aUlhne aUlhIOTh
              < 1 IOTh + Theres There res s no doubt do bl about that thats he hesaid In I n the th e solitude of my m den I ex exaniinod pxgot pxt
              t s said t with IIith a smile However How vQr thore aniinod a illod critically cllti any the imposing mpoj ng stack
              T
              then thenagr agreed agreed ed to sign a contract contractwitl contractwitlme JltraQt wit witme Witme
              me it if J could break out of Scotland ScotlandYard ScotlanYard ScotlandYard
              Yard The rhe detectives detecU s there he1e had nO nOfears n nf adfears
              fears f avs about my getting away aw y and andused andusedeasy andusecLeasy
              used usedeasy easy looks When hen I was ready readyI rendY rendYt
              t I just shook the doors doors and walked walkedx walkedout walke1out walkedout x
              out out After that I had nothing but butbig butig butbig
              big ig successes succeses all over Europe EuropeHe EuropeHe EuropeHe
              He produced his scrap book and andshowed anashowed andshowed
              showed me his hiscUppings clippings They are areundoubtedly are areundo re reundobtedly
              undoubtedly undo > abtedly a remarkable collec collection coli collection eo eotion ¬
              tion The conservative London pa papers papers papers ¬
              pers and periodicals s not only gave gavehim Iav Iavhirn gavehim
              him unlimited space but ran politi political poIiUc political ¬
              cal c l cartoons based bas d on his handcuff handcuffabilities handcuffaQiIIUcs handcuffabilities
              abilities The Thesamu same is true tnIe of f the theGerman theGerman theGerman
              German papers And Houdini does doesnot doesnot doe doenot s
              not seemed to be affected by the notorlety no notoriety notoriety ¬
              toriety he has achieved He is quite quitemodest quitemodest quit quitmodest e
              modest and unaffected unaffectedYou unaffectedYou unaffectedYou
              You would give the police p policetough mce a atough atough
              tough time > if you tenould turn crim criminal crimInal trimanal ¬
              inal I observed j
              withdanger smileis thoreIs stackof stackIs
              of police admissions r to t defeat der t t at at the thehands tho thE thEI theI
              Is no danger 1 make all the money moneyI
              hands of Houdini After all it does doesseam dUfsThe duess
              I want honestly honestlyThe honesU It
              if the sleuths are are not as a av s in invincible inthe inthe ¬
              The secret of yoa yoar oa power lies in inthe seam Qom as
              the th authors of tenccutthe tencent tencentliterature tencentmost
              vincible incible inaiblomost as
              the fact that you OU are probably tho thomost v
              literature literature would have havens vc believeRSE believe believePRANK believedoes
              most expert locksmith in the world worlddoes tibelieve
              FRANKPractically FRANK T M0 MORSE MORSEVENPALL MORSEPractically ti RSE
              does it Itnot not I inquired inquiredPractically
              Practically yes os I lean can open the theordinary VENFALL VENPALLCome VENFALLordina VENFALLCoflfe
              Come heap the leg logtl le + and > iM4 the tht > blaze biazoup hlaz hlazUP blazeordinary
              ordinary ordina r handcuff by y simply rap rapping ¬ up higher higherAnd hIgherping
              And mjike good gooay cheer h he l r ab about ° t Cta roaring roaringnre roanngthe roa yin yinfire 1 1ping
              ping it on the floor I understand understandthe mll fire nreNay
              Nay N ay butI butthe but the thethink bluebirds s h heret rei Or OrI stay stayI gt gtthe tiY tiYI tiYlmow
              the mechanism so thoroughly that I Iknow I I think thinkI
              of the thf > bobolink bobolinkatxtp HJJ Unk UnkWas
              I heard the laiUtUing
              know just how to it
              tap to make it itfly
              1 ttk ttkfly to k kfly
              Was I that Ole ash b upon a
              fly open For such easy tricks I Idont atxtp atxtpOr INlp INlpdont +
              Or Is t the blue bloom of a a pulpy pulpyffr pulp1oa pulpsdont
              dont mind allowing a II ovo f ng the spectators spectatorsto ffr grape grapeto gapetiKithhi n nWithin
              Within my chimney ch imney corners cornersgleam orner happy happygl halpye happyto
              to watch me It is when wh e n I have havesomething h a e gleamcloud gl gleam gl6llU11something un unA
              A > cloud of wlsard sprites the seasons seasonssosm aeasonsa eeasonssomething
              something very difficult to perform performthat
              seem sosmAnd a seemAnil 8J1l 8J1lthat
              that I retire into my Ghost House Houseto And nIl al U the year ye ear + a manycolored many + utored dreamQ dream dreamCan
              to Q prerreerre preserve prierve my secret secretDo Can I mistake or was t yesterevo yesterevoI yestrevoDo
              I saw th the fireflies dance the fairiesDo fairies fairiesweave fairlsu
              Do Do you u meet mee meet t many people who whosee weave weaveWas woavesee weaveWas
              Was It this morn that from his sphere sphereof spherAof
              see it ail ailOh ai a ° of flame flameLove flameOh flameLove
              Love stooped delflc uttering lt tllS my nam name < 7 7Surely 1ere
              Oh yes in every every audience There ThereIs Th ere Surely Surelyno no music mur ie or of flute or orbtrd orbtrdis bird birdLike birdL1kO
              Like Ljko the childs voice this afternoon afternoonI
              Is always some some one to cry fake But Butthere
              I hoard hoardThrough h hoardThrough rd rdthera
              there Is no fake about It It f l can canopen Through what meridians of light you youtare ou ouopen
              tareOh tare
              open open locks thats all allI Oh lovely IIf life and through what stress stressyou stressI stressyou
              you ou bear bearMy bearos bearI
              I ros rose r os to t 0 go with genuine regret regretHoudini My Iy wondering soul to this ftNner + r ratter < mer airl airlHarriot air airHoudini atriHarriot
              Harriot Prescott Pr a Ott Spooffiurd Spoott rd in Con Ccatury Contur
              Houdini is an entertaining talker tury tur
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1906-09-29/ed-1/seq-5/#words=Jail+Houdini+Harry</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              PIANO BOX FAILED TO HOLD HOUDINI
              Alter flftyaeven minutes confinement
              In a zinclped box by em
              of the Plane
              Company Harry Houdini Jail breaker
              and indcuff king who tied band amljt to a chair with a rope before
              entering the case reappeared on the
              stage at Chases last just 6n the
              stroke of midnight
              lioudioi went Into tbe box wearing an
              Immaculate stiff shirt high collar
              a wellpressed evening suit When he
              next seen collar and tie were rising hi shirt was wringing wet his
              truuscr stuck to him and his face
              ehowed plainly that he had been through
              1iore than he had expected Before
              teeing to hi dressing room HoudinI
              stated that fiftyseven the
              1 mgest time lie had ever been confined
              in any wooden box
              The box waa brought on the stage
              the and Houdlnis assist
              ant and thoroughly inspected by 90-
              0jf rsons who were to take
              eats on the stage because standing
              roim could not be procured on any
              Jloor of the playhouse
              The committee on holding Houdini
              v as composed of Chairman J W Clouse
              1 Iee Anderson Birth Charles
              Vollmer William Ziegler Earl Sanders
              and Wilt Butler Chairman douse dec id id to put a few more in
              and for fifteen minutes lila fellow
              mmitteemen straddled the case and
              imvHl into the box as fast iwdrivers could work
              tlouoinl discovered tbe box was air
              t and asked that a few small holes
              nored o a to allow him to breath
              At iu45 oclock Houdini seated
              in a chair on the platform above the
              and announced that he was
              louse and one of the theater emi took twenty yards of brand nwe half an inch in diameter and tied
              Mnidini in a way which the trickster ilinits he never bound befor
              liairman Clouse and his men thenI if M Houdini chair and rope inside the
              showed everyone thut he wee there
              then prepared to put on the lid B
              i he handed Houdini a
              stai card written a skeptical in
              iiKtual who claimed Houdini had a
              ml assisting him At 1100 Houdlnisi I house was placed
              fr the box This being done or
              atra played at a furious rate and the
              iti Jien e settled down to wait Jiut as the hands of the stage clock jointed to midnight Houdini jumped
              down oft the platform His appearance
              indicated that he had a strenuous time iusi le the case arms were scarred
              ny the rope and there were blisters on i hands Houdini handed the postalt Mr Close took his coat from the and left the stage He reap
              a moment later and assisted the Knane employee in removing the cover l the box was empty
              Houdini manufac titer of the box and said it was one of the h
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1907-09-01/ed-1/seq-36/#words=HOUDINI+Houdini</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              MRS. HOUDINIdoes not appreciate her husband, Ifear. She
              said that if the public found
              .-out how he baffled, all the po-:
              • iliccmcnin the world from St. Petersburg to" Eddy street and had risen
              ton the stepping stones of unfastened
              han<j[cu.ffs to the headine on the Or-
              :
              pheum ': bill,'.Harry f Houdini ='• would
              . cease *.t&."draw" and they 'twould have
              to..>\-ork;.for their.living;" ;.!-.. '\u25a0'} .
              .;\u25a0 ':
              :She -underrates the iuihandme, cuff-
              =,king;' When, a man 'is an Alcibiades,
              •a. Leonardo da Vinci or a Mayor Tayv lor of the vaudeville circuit,- with several hundred odd, ends and entireties
              \u25a0 ;
              c/i professions inhis.fingers and toes,"
              •
              <fan break jail with:impunity, is a real
              •Hero.''aLincoln Steffcns of prestidigitation, king of card tricksters—he per-
              'forraed fbr.:me:—and besides all that
              has'-.ihf scenario of a Krerricr melo-
              •
              drama fo-r his.biography, there is little
              .; clanger, that '\u25a0'his "wife ever woultlhave
              \u25a0to tak<i":
              inJ typewriting.' j
              .•' ."
              "
              .\u25a0\u25a0When" you saw Houdini on the Or-
              :. p.3jeu'm;stagc y;6u marveled .at his dex-
              ..terity in iindoing- - handcuffs, and' that
              \u25a0is but the .professional," the sordid,
              .'\u25a0\u25a0 side of his careerl ':
              •. ..
              "\u25a0 •
              -.' .' .
              i.:Mrs>";Houdini, •
              if. the
              '
              world: ever
              1earns Ijqw..the handcuff. trick is done
              :
              ;
              aii'd.
              ;
              the' vaudeville \ trust cancel's :the"
              "j3iea.l:/ticket, jiist*..telep-hQntf-to. the
              .nearest newspaper -shop -and get' a
              •ieady reporter whp can take dictation
              ;
              from yonr husband. ,let'Mr. Houdini
              -:'.tell the .story- of •
              life.:into /the
              5 keyboard, .get the copy printed, and
              "'serve' it hot between [lurid covers'.in
              [rhc .path' of '
              rn.essejigcE boys' and
              ilierth.v Ml Glay's impressive. cl.icnjfele.
              There's money.init at 5 cents. a. copy.
              Ho>y to Write the Biography. \u25a0
              \u25a0j -.For- instance, start",it:off this; way:
              :':'-jr. '\u25a0' -i,".CHAPTER I
              '\u25a0;'< :^';'-
              •\u25a0\u25a0.\u25a0•"'.'; The Boy 'Contortionist; ;:."•,= .•
              m "S^e \u25a0 a :
              pju .and pick' it up, then
              you'll always, liave good luck.' . ]\u25a0'
              \u25a0\u25a0 "There., was a-stir,in•Appletou, Wis.,
              on that beautiful June morning. . Life
              :\vas again worth living/ even children
              were happy; Jack Hocfler's circuswas
              •coming to,town. The stupendous ag-
              .sfegation; ;of acervative \u25a0 muchness
              Mould show iiiBill Binkers .lot at
              .2:30. The teachers of the Appleton
              school played to; empty beirches^ and ,tlic bunch at the Appleton • Grand
              hotel, did nothing but gape .at the
              circus poster showing a .beautiful
              maiden most indecorously clad play-
              !ing peek-a-boo with -a white steed
              through a paper hoop.
              "Suddenly all eyes were, turned
              from the brilliant mural decoration
              on Jones' livery stable to watch the
              egress of a wondrous damsel from
              the portals of the caravansary.. •
              *''It be her,' gasped the leading citizens. as the girl approached in queenly dignity. As she passed the group
              a glittering diamond pin fell from her
              bonnet, the point sticking into the reinforced wooden sidewalk. . ... ?^-
              Wins Job by Eyelid
              "'•l will pick it up for you, lady,'
              said a gentle voice, and a blue-eyed
              J»ciy with "curly black hair stepped
              from the . awestruck- throng. He
              ttood with his back to the pin and
              bending over until his lithe body de-
              >cribed a gothic arch, aimed one eye
              for the pinhead, closed his lids with
              decision over the jeweled setting and plucked the pin from the pavement.
              Thus did our hero, Harry Houdini,
              for itwas no other, than he. make a
              hit with the circus . lady and get a
              job in the show." ;
              .
              \u25a0
              :
              '
              :Itwould be needless forme to vouch
              for the truth of that chapter, for
              . Harry Hondini told me himself that
              he had begun life as a boy contortionist and that his first famous trick
              was picking up pins from the floor through, the ingenious prehensibility
              of his eyelids. ;\ '
              * .
              Now nearly all of our trades have their domestic as wellas their public
              side. A carpenter's talent for driving
              nails is invaluable when he wants to
              cage, the baby in the .crib and a"reporter's adroitness inusing words and
              his imagination comes in profitably
              when he has a love letter to invent,
              butIcould not at first see how Houdini ever, turned his propensity for
              getting out.of jail to advantage in a' social waj-. He doesn't look like a
              young man who would need even an •clisor. .* . ,
              In.the interest of :scieucc Iwon-- \u25a0dered if. fate had -ever been, kind enough to furnish the. opportunity to match the rare ability.
              Uses Fillmore Street Talk
              .He told me that it had. He spoke
              iiithe fluent, pliable language of Fillmore, street and not in the Parisian
              English which he uses as a stage dialect. '\u25a0_;\u25a0\u25a0\u25a0;\u25a0\u25a0;-;.; •
              [? The amanuensis might liftthis.bod- ily from the interview, even though
              and the ossified man. We were put
              in the detention cell at the calaboose,
              while the manager chased up the justice to get" our fine paid.
              "'The gang started to kidding me
              about not being able to pick a lock
              and break jailwhen Ihad to. Itook
              them up onitand before the manager
              came back we were all out all right,
              hiking back to the lot where the show
              was.. You ought to see .our pictures
              in the paper next day.' "
              Tells of14is First Feat
              Ihad in my pocket a pair of handcuffs lent to me' by Captain Frank
              Norman of Chief of Police Anderson's office and eventually Ihad intended. to try them on my victim/ So
              I\6d gently up to the subject of
              slipping out of ''prison jewelry."
              "When did you first open a handcuff?''-
              "When Iwas apprenticed to a locksmith in Appleton, Wis," he replied,
              categorically. "The town marshal
              handcuffed a man, so tight that he
              could not unlock the irons.'. He
              brought him to the locksmith's shop
              and Istarted to file away the metal,
              but made slow work. Then Igot
              the idea of picking the lock. Idid it.
              Nobody but that prisoner and myself
              know ho\v it is done. My nrst stunt
              in the show business was to untie any
              knot that .was. fastened on me—Ican
              untie knots as well witlimy toes as
              with my hands."
              .From a symposium on knots, during which Houdini expressed. his profound contempt for people who permitted '
              themselves to be irrevocably
              lashed to the mast or tied to the
              burning sta*ke, the conversation drifted to what •Houdini considered his
              mbst thrilling feat—a leap from the
              Detroit river bridge in December,
              when, ice was floating. This versatility was supernal; just the minute
              before Houdini had handed me a magazine; "The Conjurers' Monthly."
              What other .magazine editor ever
              jumped from aTbridge? But Houdini
              not only jumped from the bridge; but
              he wore handcuffs when he did it.
              In his' magazine Houdini uses the
              muckrake oh Robert Houdin, a predecessor in magic.
              "Youmust have been able to help
              people out of predicaments, Houdini,"
              I.suggested, seeking another chapter
              inthe. career of this man.
              "Iwas in a hotel, the Zum Kaiser- hof, in Hanover, Germany, in 1902
              when the place got on fire. Iopened
              the doors of 14 rooms. Icould do it quicker, than the people inside,
              could turn the keys in the locks. The proprietor said that ifIever came to
              Hanover again and stopped ,at any
              place but his there would be trouble."
              That was all he said about it,sim- ple narrative, and even those meager
              details had to be probed out of him
              with interrogation points.
              Again we let the professional matter lapse to consider the social advantages of being a lock picker. Houdini^ told me two thrilling burglar
              stories. These should go into the 5^ cent novel. Once, in Coffeyville,
              Kans.. he was forced by a gang of
              armed gamblers to pick the lock of
              a gaming den that they might get in
              to mark the cards. He picked the !
              lock successfully, but jumped quickly
              through the opened door into the area and slammed it in the face of the
              frustrated gamblers. They took a
              shot at Houdini. He showed me the bullet wound in the back of his hand.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1907-09-23/ed-1/seq-6/#words=king+handcuff+HOUDINI+Houdini</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              6
              WIZARD TOYS
              WITH POLICE
              HOUDINI HAS FUN AT JAILERS
              EXPENSE
              EASILY GETS OUT OF THEIR
              HANDCUFFS
              Man Who Releases Himself from
              Crushing Weight of Manacles
              Defeats Cleverest Men
              on the Force
              Houdlnl again baf
              fled the police and of
              ficers and escaped
              from their most dif
              ficult "hardware" last
              night at the Orphe
              um. Officers Gardner
              and La Niece, assist
              ed by Jailer Gllpln,
              fastened nearly one
              hundred and twenty
              pounds of shackles
              and handcuffs on the
              wrists and ankles of
              the "handcuff king,"
              from which it took
              him exactly eight and
              one-half minutes to
              escape.
              This is the second
              attempt made by
              these three officers to
              defeat Houdlni. On
              Saturday evening they
              handcuffed his hands
              behind his back and
              drew the chains of the
              leg Irons through the
              iandcuff chains. In this difficult posi
              tion, which compelled him to crouch upon
              his knees, it took Houdinl fifteen min
              utes to release himself.
              Gardner, La Niece and Gllpin say that
              they are not through with Houdini. and
              Houdlni says that if it gives them pleas
              ure to shackle him they are welcome
              every evening. He offered one of the
              trio a year's salary— Houdlni' s, not the
              officer's— to repeat one of the simplest
              of his tricks which the rtflcer had boast
              ed of doing. Up to date the offer has
              not been accepted.
              HOUDINI
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1907-09-29/ed-1/seq-6/#words=Jail+HOUDINI+Jails+Houdini</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          6
          HOUDINI IS
          REMINISCENT
          HANDCUFF KING TELLS STORY
          OF HIS LIFE
          THRILLING INCIDENTS CROWD
          CAREER
          Claims the Marvelous Acts He Does
          Are Simple and Makes No
          Profession of Magic
          Powers
          HY HARRY HOUDINI
          THIS is not a biography but a story.
          A biography must commence with
          the least interesting event of a
          man's life-the fact that he was born.
          That must be taken for granted in m>
          case for my story shall commence with
          the events of today and take up in re
          verse order some of the Interesting
          things that have happened to me since
          I reached that age at which every self
          respecting American boy begins to
          "shift for himself."
          This Is my second visit to Los An
          geles. The previous one was In July,
          1899 when the Orpheum was located
          In the present Grand opera house on
          Main street.
          What a transformation? In eight
          yean Los Angeles has changed almost
          beyond recognition. It was like seeing
          an old friend gone to the bad to wit
          ness the difference in Main street today
          and eight years ago when it was the
          Important Btreet and the business cen
          ter of the town.
          On reaching Los Angeles my first
          thought was of some friends and ac
          quaintances met here In 1899. My first
          visit was to the men who had chained
          and handcuffed me in my previous ap
          pearances. Captain Walter H. Auble
          and Sergeant Sam McKenzie remem-
          Wea me at once. I need not say that
          It was a great pleasure to me that they
          should do so.
          These officers recalled to me prac
          tically everything I did at the Or
          pheum here eight years ago, and Cap
          tain Auble related one of the little
          tricks of 1 magic I showed the men In a
          private exhibition given at police head
          quarters.
          Captain Auble is an excellent story
          teller and I can only approximate the
          Interesting style In which he narrated
          the event.
          "This man Houdinl gave a little ex
          hibition to the boys up In the assembly
          hall," said the captain.
          "He took a package from his pocket,
          opened It up and showed us they were
          real needles.
          Threaded In the Interior?
          "For further proof he took one of
          them and stuck It through a fold In his
          cheek, which he held between his
          thumb and finger. We saw It stick-
          Ing through about half an inch. He
          pulled It out and put it in his mouth.
          Then he took half the paper of needles
          and placed them on his tongue. Ho
          opened his mouth and showed them
          there.
          "He chewed up those needles and
          swallowed them, opened his mouth and
          showed they had disappeared. In the
          same way he chewed up and swallowed
          the other half of the package.
          "Next he put a few feet of thread
          Into his mouth and ate that, too.
          "Finally he opened his mouth and drew
          out the needles threaded, about ten
          Inches apart.
          "Now," concluded the captain, "I am
          not saying that Houdinl really swallowed
          those needles and thread or that he has
          a self-threading stomach. But I saw him
          do Just what I say, though none of the
          boys will believe the story when I tell It."
          This la not told as a proof of my
          magic powers, but as a tribute to a
          good friend's excellent memory. The trick
          was done exactly as he states. It gave
          me the greatest pleasure to know that
          my humble efforts at entertaining the
          force eight years ago have been so well
          remembered.
          Sergeant Sam McKenzle was one of the
          men who shackled me on the Orpheum
          satge.
          "I made a good job of it. too," says
          Sam. "There was no faking about that.
          But you got out. Perhaps I will try it
          again before you leave Los Angeles,
          though I haven't much hopes of beating
          you."
          Cuffs Must Be Regular
          ' The one unpleasant feature of my visit *-
          - here had Its origin in that same visit to b
          ¦ police headquarters. I think when Detec- c
          tive Tom Rico offered to bet a thousand c
          ;. dollars ' (or was It a million?) that he
          had . a cuff from which I could not es
          •' cape he . was not serious and that the
          i challenge ; was made Jokingly, for he
          I made no offer to post any money, though r
          ! I gave him every opportunity to do so. c
          Probably the joshing to which he was c
          subjected by other officers and. the news- r
          I paper reporters nerved him to make the r
          unfair attempt on Monday evening last, a
          ' in " which Nhe was so ignomlnlously de
          . feated. ->.-.' ¦¦¦¦'¦¦' : •¦¦¦'.
          1 ; As | there has been . a • great deal of | I
          I comment on this matter I shall say just '
          ¦ a few words about It. .
          '¦¦? ¦ Let :me say <In preface that I unlock '
          ,5 every handcuff that Is placed upon me. '
          II I do not merely slip them over my hands. '
          !tl have a large hand. If a lock is plugged '
          .* or broken or is not in proper working or- i
          der or for any other reason cannot be un- ]
          locked it Is barred. This Is only reason
          able, for I do not pretend to have magic '
          powers. My methods are of the simplest i
          S and i are . all perfectly natural. Since I :
          '¦* open the cuffs It is a part of my challenge
          S that i they . must not be . "faked" or tam
          £ pered with. 'To Insure this I demand the
          ; , right to ' Inspect every manacle before It
          •< is. placed upon me. ¦¦ .' ; -
          ¦B Last . Monday ¦ evening Tom | Rico sent
           his nephew, Louis Rico, to the Orpheum
          with a pair of tampered cuffs. ; When my
          ?. Invitation was given Louis Rico .and oth
          ;¦ ers 5 came : upon the stage. Louis Rico
          .? showed 'me ' a pair of regulation cuffs in<
          i perfect working order. When I held out
          my hands to him to be manacled he sub
          stituted another pair while my back had
          been i turned. \ One -of these was on my
          'wrist and my assistant gave me a secret
          cue. which he had been. Instructed to
          V, use, to i. warn -me of danger. ; I then took
          i the other ouff and snapped it. Rico was
          • nonplused. '..¦¦'. . ...
          »Z'"l demanded that he unlock the cuff and
          permit me to examine it. Ho replied that
          [ he had not the key. for it. -(I afterward
          I learned that he had the key in his pocket
          at ; the;. time.) j He said, he would have to
          '"¦V send for Tom to bring. the key. He sent
          S off a messenger : to •¦ the \ police • station
          ¦'? and < I ;! took , the opportunity .to • tell the
          •audience what had taken place. ¦•
          , * Says Cuff Is Unfair
          |w»I. offered to wager $100 against Rico's $6
          'fi that the cuff had been "fixed." Why did
          he not accept? TfTe answer is plain. .He
          '& knew.; that Ihe had ; done , an ' underhanded
          ¦ trick and did not want to lose $6. because
          he knew I could prove his guilt at the
          I? time. Sji, '¦, '.";• ;¦•.-.;¦:,' •, ...'¦ ,:; ¦¦'.•.
          "Then j 1 .. retired 'tojmy .' cabinet .' and ". in
          ri forty minutes .'; opened • Rico's ¦ tampered
          ty cuff. .lT ; handed the cuff back to, the man
          f '¦ opened ; and • unlocked, £ and ' repeated ¦ my
          offer to wager $100 against his $5 without
          ft] a response from ; him. v Surely.: there . was
          ss ' among i the , bunch. >V ,;;. gghB^gBMB B
          There , was ', nothing especially . difficult
          K' about, the handcuffs produced. by Rico, If
          V*, they/ had been : in ' good order." They : were
          ¦ J what is known as the Marlln or Bottle
          .'- neck cuff, r paten ted: by a ! Callfornlan. A
          . ': good cuff, but offering no great difficulties
          LOS ANGELES HUKAI.D: SUNDAY MOISMNO. SEPTEMBER 29, 1907.
          Harry Houdini, Wizard of Manacle and Cabinet Tells the Story of His Interesting Career
          EIGHT PAIRS OF HANDCUFFS PUT ON BY LOB ANGELES DETECTIVES
          - ... ..:.•¦¦,.• +".-- -:--- v •¦¦•;... ,^i '»c Tl pn WtTrQPES BY SAILORS . ™^ ; . ESCAPE FROM THE GUITEAU CELL
          hanwuffedandchaneVtob^ ** i» •» v RflAßiikf*! cc apop* r m ainq ill Wl P I NTO LAKE AT EST LAKEPA Rf\
          ,„:-!• .... - HOUDINI, LADEN WITH WlftNAk/L ta «" u vn '"' «"•"•-» .....:. i 1- ............
          if not tampered with. I have negotiated
          this class of cuff many hundred times.
          Looking out of my hotel window I see
          a street car passing which bears the an
          nouncement "Houdinl will dive from the
          pavilion roof, heavily handcuffed, in West
          lake park, Saturday at 12:30 noon." By
          the time this Is printed that will be yes
          terday, and I have every hope that I shall
          still be alive. Should I fail to get those
          cuffs loose before my breath gives out
          you can imagine where I am while you
          are reading this.
          Among the feats of similar character
          that I have carried through might be
          mentioned the leap from the Seventh
          street bridge in Pittsburg, Pa., sixty feet
          into the icy waters of the Allegheny river.
          A crowd which is said to have numbered
          nearly 60,000 persons lined the bridge and
          the banks of the river to witness this. In
          December last I leaped from the Belle Isle
          bridge into the Detroit river in the pres
          ence of one of the largest crowds that
          ever assembled in that ctiy.
          Remarkable Escapes
          Last Friday, which will be the last Fri
          day week when you read this, I was
          nailed Into a strong packing case by the
          employes of the J. M. Hale Co., and the
          case was then strongly roped by the samp
          men. I believe that It took nearly eight
          minutes for me to escape wtihout leaving
          any indication of my means of egress.
          Among similar performances which
          have attracted much attention from the
          press was escaping from a box made,
          nailed and roped by the packers of the
          Henry Slegel store in Boston, and tn
          closed in another larger box which also
          was nailed and roped by the same par
          ties. I have a handsome gold medal pre
          sented to me by the Siegels In com
          memoration of this event, which took
          place on the 25th of Janvary last.
          I have been confined In packing cases,
          leather mall pouches, paper sacks, cof
          fins, wicker baskets, tin-lined piano cases,
          roll topped desks, casks, plate glass cases
          with steel angle irons and a sheet steel
          steam holler. All these events are de
          tailed in the daily papers of Boston and
          Toledo during the months of February
          and March last. Can you imagine a city
          with the reputation for staidness and
          dignity which Boston boasts, going Hou
          dinl crazy? It Is hard, but it is true, and
          pleasant for me. Nothing that ever
          visited Boston, except Tom Lawson, has
          attracted as much attention or received
          so much newspaper notoriety as I and
          my act last February.
          But I am going backward faster than
          was my intention. Let us get ahead
          again. In San Francisco two weeks ago
          a curious challenge was issued to me
          and accepted. Sailors often boast that
          whaf they cannot do with ropes is not
          worth doing. The men of the cruiser St.
          Louis, then in Frisco harbor, challenged
          me to escape Irom their nairtlcal knots.
          They roped and bound me much in the
          manner that the spider does his victims,
          but not with gossamar webs. Let me
          assure you that the cordage which Uncle
          Sam supplies to his navy is of the best.
          It will neither stretch nor slip when
          knotted by half a dozen stout tars. Did
          I escape? les. but it was a hard trfcl.
          When the last knot was loosed I was
          so exhausted that I could scarcely bow
          my acknowledgments to the applause
          that followed. I will also say that I
          was unable to escape until every knot
          was undone. They left me no chance to
          slip or wrisKle through their meshes.
          Fights on the Square
          I do not relish the thought of a similar
          experience, but as a public performer It
          is almost compulsory for me to take up
          any challenges of this character that are
          offered. I approach every new challenge
          with uncertainty for sometime I. shall
          meet my Waterloo. In every caivor there
          comes b Gettysburg, and I so to mine.
          Well, when it comes I shall say— "l
          have fought a good fight, und I have
          fought fair." When I am vanquished
          fairly I will admit defeat like a man,
          but I demand fair and square opponents.
          »ye I ever been defeated in a chal
          i? No, never. I have had many
          Lrrow escapes. I have been caught
          napping by men who laid their brains
          against mine, but always some subtle
          instinct has warned me when a trap
          has been laid for me. Scarcely a week
          passes but someone, falling to defeat
          me by fair means, resorts to trickery.
          My experience with men of this class
          keeps me forever on the alert.
          The nearest that I ever came to de
          feat was In the town of Blackburn,
          England, where I appeared at the Pal
          ace theater In October, 1902. The chal- j
          lenger was a man named Hodgson, who
          seemed to accept my public appearance
          in Blackburn as a sort of personal af- |
          front to him in his capacity of principal ,
          of a school of physical culture. H* ,
          challenged me in a way that left him j
          open to do almost anything he chose to .
          me. I saw that the challenge was al- j
          together favorable to him. but clrcum- j
          stances compelled my acceptance. The |
          cuffs which Hodgson brought had been I
          tampered with In various ways, and
          this was not denied by him, but he
          claimed that the terms of the challenge
          left him the privilege. He chose to
          follow the letter of the challenge and
          cast aside every thought of good
          sportsmanship or professional good
          feeling. It wa3 to be a battle a l'out
          rance.
          Imposes a Cruel Test
          First he fixed a pair of irons over
          my upper arm, passing the chain be
          ln.d my back and drawing it tight
          with all his great strength. To make
          assurance doubly sure he (lxed another
          pair In the same Vay. Both were pad
          locked behind*
          Then he placed handcuffs on my
          wrists so that my arms, already pulled
          stiffly backward were now drawn for
          ward.' In vain I protested that he was
          almost breaking my arms. Up to that
          time he had the assistance of another
          person, also a man. of great strength,
          and the united Efforts of the two were
          devoted to tightening the Irons to the
          limit. A second pair of cuffs were
          placed on my wrists, trussing my
          arms so securely that there seemed no
          possibility of moving them.
          Finally he forced me to kneel down,
          and shackeling my ankles passed the
          chain of the leg Irons through the
          chain that bound my elbows together
          behind my back. This chain was also
          doubled and drawn tight so that I re
          mained kneeling with my feet drawn
          almost up to the middle of my back.
          Will you please try this position for
          half a minute without irons and en
          deavor to Imagine how I felt shackled
          in that way?
          My little ghost house was placed
          over me, for I could not move to get
          into it. I fell on my side and could not
          rise to my knees. After fifteen min
          utes Hodgson permitted as a favor that
          I should be lifted up to my knees. 1
          struggled for twenty minutes without
          avail. It seemed that my career was
          ended. My arms were numb and blood
          less. The circulation was almost en
          tirely suspended. I pleaded to have
          the cuffs removed for a minute that the
          circulation might bo restored. Hodg
          son refused unless I would admit de
          feat. A doctor In the audience came
          on the stage and examined me and
          stated that my arms were blue and that
          it was dangerous to keep me chained
          longer. But I would not surrender
          and Hodgson would not concede an
          lota.
          Undergoes Terrible Ordeal
          Fifty minutes after the manacles were
          attached I had succeeded in freeing oiip
          band, and never did heartier cheers greet
          a p rforiner Ulan wore accorded me when
          I thrust back the curtain and showed one
          handcuff opened and my hand freed.
          At the end of. two hours I jra# free.
          HEAVILY SHACKLED IN GERMAN COURT ROOM
          But my clothing was torn to shreds, my
          arms and hands were bleeding. Even the
          thunder of applause was no compensation
          for that awful two hours. Never again
          will I submit to a challenge that means
          physical torture such as that. The game
          Is not worth the candle.
          One of my experiences In Germany is
          worthy of record, for It was at once a
          vindication and a just punishment to an
          autocratic and unfair public official. This
          happened in the city of Cologne In Feb
          ruary of the year 19C2.
          The German police are very strict in
          their supervision of amusements, and no
          false billing or misrepresentations of ex
          hibitions is permitted. They prosecute
          offenders against such regulations under
          the charge of obtaining money by false
          p.
          Schutzrnann Werner Graff, chief of the
          Cologne police, endeavored to secure cvi- 1
          dence that would convict me of misrepre
          sentation, and failing in this he published
          a false story in the Rheinische Zeituns.
          an Influential newspaper, which put me
          and my performance In a very bad light.
          As a foreigner It seemed a difficult mat
          ter for me to prosecute the chief of polloo
          of Cologne; yet that I did so and secured
          a verdict against him for slander Is an
          eloquent tribute to the uncorruptible Jus
          tice of the German laws and courts.
          Engaging the best possible legal talent,
          I entered suit against Graff for slandor.
          The case was tried through all the courts
          and "the costs ran into the thousands. In
          every court the verdict was favorable
          to me, and Graff was sentenced to pay
          all «costs and a fine or spend a day In
          Jail for each five marks of the costs and
          fine. As the imprisonment would have
          figured out Into something like five years
          Graff paid up like a mun.
          Invites Challenges
          It was the method by which the judges
          decided this case in the higher courts that
          makes this case worthy of special In
          terest. They were not governed by law,
          precedents, technicalities or rules of evi
          dence but by facts. The point to be de
          cided, said the judges In effect, Is this:
          Does Houdlni open locks and handcuffs
          In the manner he claims? After I had
          done my usual stunts In the court the
          police produced a special lock, so mads
          that after it was locked it could not he
          opened with Us own or any other key.
          This lock they challenged me to open, or
          admit myself beaten. On the result de
          pended the decision of the judges. I ac
          cepted, walked Into a room selected by
          the judges, where I could work unhin
          dered, and in four minutes re-entered the
          I and handed the open lock to the
          ing judge,
          all my experience the only men I
          met who will not admit defeat arc
          who use unfair means. In thla
          the trickster was ordered by the
          to make public apology, which was
          shed in all the principal papers of
          the city, and lately I have heard he h;is
          resigned from the police department. The
          shame and stigma In Germany last long.
          A map of my wanderings In America
          and Europe would be practically a repro
          duction of any standard and up-to-date
          railway map. I have not missed many
          cities, and those I have missed are so far
          back that they have not missed me.
          The record of my first appearance in
          England is but a fair sample of the treat
          ment accorded me everywhere. As a pro
          fessional I have every reason to be proud
          of it. When' I sailed from New York on
          Decoration day, 1900, I had not even the
          promise of an engagement. After several
          private exhibitions given before the Lon
          don managers I was given a contract for
          two weeks, but my engagement with that
          manager was prolounged to the end of
          August, and I returned to the same
          theater for a second engagement in De
          cember of the same year. So it has been
          everywhere. And after all these yearß
          and all this travel in every part of
          Europe and America there are still those
          who cry •¦Fake." It IS to these that I
          owe my challengers, and therefore I
          should be JhanJUul (that .there Is such a
          thing aa unconvincible scepticism. It Is I
          these challenges that lend spice to my
          existence.
          Visits Many Prisons
          Probably no other man has visited so |
          many of the great prisons of the world I
          as I have. My prolesalon has brought
          me into touch with the prison and
          police authorities everywhere and they
          have all been kind enough to explain
          how securely their prisoners are held,
          and to show me that it is quite impos
          sible for their charges to escape. All |
          of which made my escapes from these
          same prisons tlie more interesting and
          instructive It has also been my good
          fortune to De able to point out on more
          than one occasion where weak spots
          existed in their systems, and I have
          received the unsolicited acknowledge
          ments of more than one Jailer and
          sheriff to this effect.
          My reputation as "the international
          Jailbreaker" was not won on paper. It
          Is not merely an advertising catch
          word. A few of my exploits in this
          line have attracted adverse attention
          from the governments interested, but
          usually the authorities have acknowl
          edged that the escape of Houdinl from
          their prisons did not mean that the
          prison could not hold the men for whom
          It was designed.
          The following list of my escapes In
          cludes only the most famous ones:
          San Francisco, Cal., July 1899.
          Siberian transport cell May, 1903.
          Old prison foordrecht, Holland. Sep-
          Sheffleld, England, January, 1904.
          Liverpool, England, February, 1902.
          Kansas City, Mo., April, 1900.
          Beilln, Germany, September, 1900.
          Huddersfield, England, November,
          The Gutteau cell No. 2, murderers'
          row, Washington, D. C, Jail, January,
          City prison, Boston, Mass., March,
          All Jails Fail
          Do not suppose that these are by any
          means all the Jails that have failed to
          hold me. They are the ones that come
          readiest to my memory. Of almost
          every one of these I have attested cer
          tificates signed by the officers of the
          prison In each case and by prominent
          persons and officials who witnessed the
          performance.
          The most secure prison In the world
          is supposed to be the cells or "carettes,"
          Ithich prisoners destined for Siberia
          transport**. Yet from this I es
          dln less than twenty minutes. Be
          enterlng the cell I was submitted
          , severe searching by the secret
          ;e. Never have I been so thorough
          earched as by these officers, who
          alnly know that part of their busi
          i. The search was conducted and
          escapa accomplished In the presence
          he chief of the secret or spy police
          doscow, Russia. After accompllsh
          thls feat the management of the
          Zoo Gardens, where I was performing,
          did me the honor of doubling the salary
          previously paid me.
          Warden J. H. Harris of the Wash
          ington, D. C.i United States Jail was
          sitting comfortably In his office one
          day in January last year, when a
          stranger entered and asked to be
          locked up.
          "Why do you want to be locked up?"
          asked the surprised warden.
          "So I can break out," was the stran
          ger's strange reply.
          The warden had never seen me, and
          as it is my custom to do this sort of
          stunt without previous warning he was
          not expeoting me. It did not take long
          to explain the situation, and in a few
          minutes the warden had collected a
          large crowd of the officials of the Jail
          and their friends to see the first au
          thorized attempt to break out of Wash
          ington Jail.
          The warden was kind enough to otter
          MANACLKS AND CHAINS WSIGH 150 POUNDS
          me my choice of cells, but I merely re
          quested to be shown the strongest. He
          took me at once to murderers' row, and
          Indicated No. 2, the cell in which Gui
          teau, the absassin of President Garfleld.
          was confined. This he said was the
          strongest cell In the Jail. I asked to
          be confined in it.
          "Unfortunately it Is occupied," said
          Warden Harris, but at rqy earnest
          solicitation the prisoner — a convicted
          wife murderer — was given a cellmate —
          myself.
          The officials stripped me to the skin,
          locked me into the cell and retired to
          await developments.
          It was with a feeling the nearest to
          terror that I have ever felt that I
          looked about me In that awful cell that
          for many years has never been without
          a tenant whose days were destined to
          end In the hangman's noose. The
          walls of the cell are of brick, concrete
          and steel, not less than three feet in
          thickness. The door, of heavy steel
          bars, is sunk into the wallß fully three
          feet from the outer face of the wall.
          When this heavily constructed door is
          closed an armrufis out to the corridor
          side of the wall and slips over a steel
          catch which sets a spring and fastens
          the lock. The latter Is one of the most
          secure of such inventions and has no
          less than seven tumblers, which, it will
          be said, is impossible to pick.
          How I got out of that cell would
          make an Interesting story that I may
          write some day after I get through
          doing my act on the stage and retire to
          devote my declining: years to Iterary
          pursuits. I could not stay — I had to go.
          The surroundings were such that no
          honest man would consent to remain.
          As I looked into the cell after my es
          cape I wondered that I had ever con
          sented to be locked into a chamber
          with such gruesome history and asso
          ciations.
          Plays Joke on Officials
          It then occurred to me to play a joke
          on the officials who were awaiting my
          return in the warden's office.
          I have a clipping from the Washington
          Post of Sunday, January 7, 1906, which
          tells the rest of the story so well that I
          cannot do better than offer it in full:
          "In two minutes Houdini was out of
          that cell, free, the lock holding htm hard
          ly longer than it took him to get into the
          place and get his bearings. Then, with
          out the knowledge of the waiting officials
          who had retired from view, Houdinl
          quickly ran to the cells of Chase, Whit
          ney, Mercer, Ferguson, Donovan, Gas
          ktns, Backus and Howlett. To each oc
          cupant the unclad cell-breaker seemed
          like an apparition from some other world,
          and the astonishment he created when he
          commanded each to come out and follow
          him can be better Imagined than de
          scribed.
          "Chase gave a gasp of fear, and then
          cried: 'Have you come to let me out?
          What are you doing without clothes?'
          He supposed then that Houdinl was an
          escaping fellow prisoner. He followed at
          Houdinl's heels and the cell breaker
          dashed with him down to the end of the
          corridor, where he opened the cell con
          taining Clarence Howlett.
          " 'What are you doing here?' said Hou
          dinl to the astonished Howlett. 'What
          are you in for?'
          " 'I'm a housebreaker,' said the pris
          oner, as though maKlng his last confes
          sion.
          " 'You're a bad one,' said Houdinl, 'or
          you could get out of here. Come along.'
          Howlett followed his strange captor, and
          Houdini then thrust Chase Into the cell
          and rushed Howlett up to Chase's cell.
          "This scene, strange and strenuous, was
          repeated again and again, until every
          desperate man was changed into another
          cell than his own, All were in a tumult.
          Twenty-one minutes after Houdini had
          been locked in the cell he had done all
          the (julck changing and stood before his
          free audience In the main hall, clothed as
          in every day manner.-. "' .'¦'"•.
          "When the officials found what he had \
          done . with their prisoners their amaze
          ment passed all bounds. They took the ¦
          slight change ' Houdinl made *In their ;
          plans with the utmost good nature, and
          soon had everything straightened out,
          and each of the men back In his cell."
          Has Certificate of Event
          RHas Certificate event presented
          certificate of this event presented
          to me by "Warden Harris Is one of my ¦
          treasures. ' In a New York deposit vault
          I have a box containing nearly one hun
          dred such certificates, with which I shall
          paper .my study when : I get too old to .
          repeat the feats they describe.
          Now, what shall I add? There Is so .\
          much to tell that I must stop somewhere .
          short of a complete history. \ '"''¦' f-"^i!
          Perhaps the most concise method Is for .
          me to let you ask a *ew questions. „Be
          gin then. . - _,' ¦ ¦
          Where was I born? In Appleton, Wis.,
          What was my first stunt. Conducting
          the Punch and Judy snow in a circus.
          Next I did a knot untying turn. Finally
          I graduated into the handcuff act. This
          I was absolutely the first t, attempt. (
          What else can I do? Well, a few of the . v
          things I -am doing today may supest
          what I should do if my present act should
          throw me down. '-., : ¦ • •¦¦¦
          I am a magician. I have some. tricks
          in 'what is commonly called magic that
          are said by the experts for whom 1 have
          It else can I do? Well, a few of any;
          I am doing today may suggest
          [ should do if my present act should
          me down.
          1 a magician. I have some tricks
          at is commonly called magic that
          id by the experts for whom I have
          them to be unapproached by any
          other performer in the - same line, and
          especially in the manipulation of cards,
          These would keep the wolf from the door,
          as long as I have the use of my hands. t
          I am an athlete and a contortionist, as ¦
          you know " you have seen me get out of
          the raightjacket. -. ; ;
          Pleasure in Magazine
          : But the thing !in which ¦^ take i most ;
          pleasure is my magazine. • This publica- *
          tion is the recognized organ of a 11^magi
          clans.":Its columns , are. their f orunu. , To
          it— which means to '¦¦ me-are referred : al
          of what appears in its columns. - . . _
          I There lis one more . question that _ you
          want answered, but : it is the .one that I
          m ,,. t ' refuse "• You want .to know how l
          ™c from' handcuffs, shackles, Oregon
          hoots • steel prison ' cells, - packing cases
          an°d tS all S th cce c other contrivances that are
          prepared for my detention. That I sha
          cV mT You^or X
          can't be true -o would not be such a
          fool as to tell' the real method.
          When the right man guesses the right
          TV" 2W or a not tO S? 3?1 TuTdo
          the act and the rest of the world will go
          "Ano^r" would!b°e re solver of my little
          mystery waV a great scientist of Dort
          mystery whs » Pro f Jansen Bartha
          =££iT3 •BESTS-
          I oniy try to U en ? ter?a Yiny in > in ') aMegltlmate
          I^only^ryio tna t;when I, leave here
          manner. /, : : trusty nai ,g, g
          win'have "as ' P^a?ln? J recollections .of
          ™ ttl a,?!!j t shall haveiof Los Angeles.f3
          former and now I have returned pros
          lormcr, a." afu] . Once again be
          fceTX Thope to visit this city' pro-
          JmlnrullT It would be pleasant to close
          mv Htaee ' career here and settle down
          Umon<£ the orange groves for the rest ot
          lamongjhe ore 6 HOUPINU j'
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1907-09-29/ed-1/seq-5/#words=king+handcuff+Houdini+HOUDINI</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              CROWD HAS
              WILD THRILLS
              HANDCUFFED MAN LEAPS INTO
              THE LAKE
              REMAINS BENEATH WATER AN
              INTERMINABLE TIME
              Harry Houdini Gives Throng of Spec
              tators In Westlake Park Two
              Minutes of Suspense While
              Submerged
              Five thousand spectators held their
              breath in sympathy with Harry Hou
              dini at Westlake park yesterday after
              noon when the handcuff marvel did a
              Count of Monte Crlsto stunt by leaping
              into the lake heavily manacled.
              "OOoo! I bet he's drowned," said a
              small boy in awed and shuddery tones
              when the man remained what seemed
              an interminable time beneath the shim
              mering water of the lake.
              A small line of bubbles came to the
              surface. Then larger bubbles arose
              and a little cloud of mud drifted to tho
              top. Five thousand shivers ran down
              5000 spines.
              "Oh, why doesn't he come up?" asked
              a nervous old lady who had waited
              HOUDINI, AS HE APPEA"ED WHEN
              HE LEAPED INTO LAKE YES.
              three hours for the opportunity to
              worry about the fate of the misguided
              youth.
              "He's unlocking the shackles. Ho
              will be up in a minute or two," said a
              high school girl.
              "Oh, dear, a minute or two Is enough
              for him to drown In," was the dismal
              reply.
              • "Aw, he's stalling," shouted an Irre
              pressible urchin.
              "No he's not. He has to get them
              shackles off first. He can't swim with
              them on." This from a bright lad with
              a wire bridle on his teeth who waited
              two hours and went home with an
              autograph which read: "Harry Hand
              cuff Houainl." '
              A man on the landing threw off his
              coat and ran to the edge of the planks
              looking intrntly into the water.
              "He's going to jump," shouted the
              throng.
              "He's stuck In the mud. Someone
              has got to rescue him," shouted a wise
              guy who had seen Houdini Jump from
              a bridge thirty feet high into 300 feet
              of water or 300 feet high into thirty
              feet of water. The crowd never got It
              straight.
              More bubbles. More mud. Then
              Houdini canre slowly to the surface —
              feet first!
              "I told you he'd stuck his head into
              the mud." said the wise guy. Then the
              feet disappeared. A second later Hou
              dini's head bobbed to the surface. He
              made it dramatic and shivery enough to
              satisfy even the small gamin who had
              half hoped to see a drowning or at least
              aTthrllHuK rescue scene.
              Laden with heavy chains and hand
              cuffs enough to restrain the county
              road gang Houdini leaped from the
              roof of the pavilion at Westlake park.
              His hands were shackled behind him.
              TbTM biff uatrolmen attended to that
              little detail. There are some members
              of the force who would have liked to
              have defeated the handcuff king even
              beneath the water.
              With no free hand to guide him in
              the headlong dive the man's body shot
              forward in an almost horizontal posi
              tion. With an indescribable midair
              kick he righted himself and made a
              pretty but dangerously vertical dive.
              The shutters of 800 cameras clicked In
              unison and the awful suspense began.
              The horror only ended when the man's
              smiling face appeared above the water
              of the lake.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1914-07-16/ed-1/seq-16/#words=Houdini+Harry</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              CROWD OF 15.000
              WATCHES HOUDINI
              Handcuff Expert, Shackled and
              Boxed. Is Thrown Into Water
              Rises in a Minute.
              Fifteen thousand people in Battery
              Park yesterday noon, cither saw or
              tiied to sec Harry Houdini, known a?
              the '?handcuff k,r.j.r." thrown into the
              water from the tug J. A. McAllister.
              The cro\?'d surged back aril forth
              the water fronl with such force
              that those in the front row alonn the
              ???a wall ' eed ab? tit mi'I, aided by po?
              licemen, ri: I ack into the
              park '
              pu-he(I into ' ? I n ''.or.
              In the meantim? Houd ?,. ?vas having
              all} hard t ?me .?ii\ inu a**:
              nio\ir, picture photographers who in?
              sisted upon reeling off his font di
              id thai he had his 0?vn staff of
              film-makeri on hand.
              All these little troubles being ? I
              tied, the newspapermen put the leg
              irons and two pair of handcuff on
              He ?va- then p;i: ii a pack?
              ing box, the cover was nailed down and
              boui '? ' ?tl steel tape, the whiatli
              the tugboat end the "P. D, 7" I
              rerboard ?vent the box, Houdini
              and -dl.
              In about one minute he appeared al
              the surface. He had done it once be?
              fore a-id had lived to hear the crowds
              cheer him The spectator
              r ting, some sr.ying that he k.-pt
              the ke; s - h ick hair, other? thai
              art -  ! genius.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1915-12-08/ed-1/seq-14/#words=Willard+Houdini</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              Jen? Willard has left Los Angeles il
              a dreadful hutf. <>i. Monday night on?
              Week ago the h:g champion attended i
              show at the Orprieiiin in that c ty ant
              hid himself in the balcony. Houdin.
              the handcuff king, was on the bill, an.
              the audience did not know that Jes?
              was la the house until Houdini, an i<
              Utual in his act, stepped to the foot
              lights and asked that a comm ttee ol
              gentlemen come up on the ttsge to ?c?
              ? the I rtegofl ! i "' apscislist hat
              nothing up hi< aleevoa ttt deceive s
              gullible public. Ten good men anri
              true meandered op to the ?tage, and
              then Hoodini said:
              "Now, I need three more gentlemen
              up here There la a men here to-night
              who doea not knoe thet I am swore "I
              his presence. Hi- will be enough fot
              gentlemen if he will
              ? ? ? on thia committee, He ia ?'??*?
              Willsrd, our champion." Taken bv sur
              priae, the ant for
              ? tecond or two and tl.?n broke info
              tumultuou- ? been and
              thrieki foi W llard filled the hoeae,
              Houdini looked up in the banlcony
              where Willard was seated und sa.?i:
              "I will leave it to the audience, Mr.
              Willard. Yyu BOS they want to see
              you."
              A fresh outburst of applause went
              up foi
              "Aw g'wan with your act." grow.el
              W r.l when the applaoae hud sub
              puled | bit. "I pan! fur mv seat here.'
              "Rut, Mr. Willard," broke in Houdini,
              .....
              uGi?e me the same wagea you pay
              those other fellows and I'll come
              down," said Willard sullenly.
              By thi? time the audience had be?
              come quite still.
              "Sir, 1 will ??la lly do to," returned
              Houdini hotly. "Come on down I pay
              these men nothing."
              "Aw g'wan with the show." roared
              Willard. Then the audience took a
              hand. Beginning with a few hisse?, a
              general demonstration against Willard
              was launched in a fla-h. Houdini held
              up his hand for silence. It was readily
              gr: iited.
              "Jess Willard, I have just paid you
              a compliment," began Hottdlni dramati?
              cally. "Now, I watit tu tell you some?
              thing else. I will be Henry Houdini,
              Je-,?. Willard, when you are NOT the
              heavyweight champion of the world."
              A roar of Bpplsoaa greeted Houdini'?
              remarks. A deep rumble In the gal?
              lery Indieeted that Willsrd was trying
              to make sonic? sort .if reply, and the
              Chsen for Hoodini suddenly veered
              to groans and Loots. ??[ made a mis
              ? take," continued Houdini. "I asked
              Boxing Bouts
              for the Week
              ritlDAT.
              New Polo A. C?A. .>,.. 8ho?.
              SATURDAY.
              F?lri???t A. C ? Young Ho?n?r and Wllll?
              Ada AMI? Na--li and Jimmy Duffy, franklg
              Oil? gnd Johnny Fill?.
              Clermont A. C? Zulu Kid and J?rT tmlth.
              Stiark.y A. C?All-alar oa/d.
              gentlemen, and only gentlemen, to step
              up on this at?go."
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1916-04-18/ed-1/seq-1/#words=Munsey+HOUDINI+HARRY</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              Houdini to Be Hanged
              In Straitjacket at High
              Noon Here Tomorrow
              "Handcuff King" to Dangle 100
              Feet In Air Before Crowds
              At 12:30 o'clock.
              WILL .EXTRICATE HIMSELF
              Expert Knot Tiers Will Superintend Exhibition, to Which All
              Are Invited.
              Harry Houdlnl has heen cordcmned)
              to be hanged! i
              Ho will bo hanged at 12:30 tomorrow
              In front of the Munsoy building In plain
              view of all of tho thousands of Wash-lngtnr.tawho can gather on Pennsylvania, avenuo.
              The "Handcuff King" has escaped
              from ovciythlng tho pollco or saVty-llr- st
              artists of all sorts havo designed
              to confine a vicious criminal and now
              ho will reach tho end of hit rope! .
              Tho end of tho rope will danglo 100
              feet In mldnlr from the front of tho.
              Munsey building and Houdlnl will bol
              attached to it by tho feet with, all tho
              Ingenious knots the police or anybody
              elan can devise .
              Arms To Bo Rigid. I
              Ho wil also havo his arms securely I
              bourn, to his body and his body made rigid with the most approved type of
              straltjacket. All of these things will
              be done to Insure the thorough hanging
              of tint worker of magic.
              And Houdlnl doclarea he will hang
              only long enough to loose himself from
              His lncumorances!
              He laughs at tho proposition to hang
              him. and declares those In charge of
              the operation can go as far as they
              like. He guarantees that he will free
              himself. And It Is agreed that he shall
              go fieo If ho docs get loose.
              Tho rrocidura to be followed will bo
              to confine Houdini in a regulation straltjacket. A Jacket and two husky attendants have been secured. The men are experienced In restraining dai.gcioiudy Insane patients. They havo been instructed to use the most ap- proved Jacket a tvpo from which no
              escape has ever been recorded. Houdini hasn't seer, the Jacket that vlll bo used apd will not see it until they put It on him The two attendants will see to It that tho "Handcuff King"
              Is placid in tho Jacket In a way they havo of putting men in Jicketa of the
              samo kind for keeps. They state they
              will put Houdlnl in the jirket for keeps,
              as no ono they havo over put into one of them has ever gotten out.
              In Air 100 Feet.
              Then a rone will bo nttached tn Hon.
              dlnl's fet so that It will not come oil
              ana tacKlo will bo attached to this
              rope with which Houdlnl will be hoisted up about 100 feet and will dangle,
              head down for
              The exact length of time he will dan- gle Is all up to Houdlnl. Tho men
              In charge will do It so well that they Insist he will dangle until they let him down. Houdini thinks otherwise. He claim ho will be thero long enough for an average person to wriggle an oyellu about three times in deliberate succession.
              Ho wants Just a minute or two and then ho claims he will free himself, throw off the straltjacket and when he wave his arms, tho tackle men
              aro to let htm down. Put he will not be lowered until ho hns relvnecd himself ibsolutely from thn straltjacket.
              Tho tltnn Ih tomorrow.
              Thu pluca Is In front of the Jlumey building. r.veniody In Washington Is Invited
              to cheer Houdlnl or thu policemen
              and nsylum attendants who think ho can't get nway.

        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1918-01-06/ed-1/seq-34/#words=jail+Houdini</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              Houdini Has New
              Elephant Trick
              To-morrow at the Hippodrome one
              ; may sec a full sized, real, live elephant
              disappear in full view of the audience
              on a brilliantly lighted stage, before
              one's very eyes. This vanishing ele?
              phant illusion is an experiment con?
              ceived and perfected by Houdini,
              world renowned expert in extracation,
              whom Charles Dillingham has selected
              as ?i feature extraordinary of "Cheer
              Up!" Tiie engagement of Houdini is
              I it. keeping with Mr. Dillingham's policy
              , o? introducing important new features
              ; ?n his big Hippodrome spectacles after
              ' the holidays.
              The disappearing elephant feat is
              i ono which Houdini began cxpcriment
              ! ing upon during his visit to India four
              years ago, for it has long been the
              dream'of the Indian fakirs to realize
              I the reputation given to Chaucer hun?
              dreds of years ago, when he wrote that
              ; he had seen "an elephant crumble to
              1 the earth in piecemeal and then reas
              i semble itself and walk away." Hou
              | dini's illusion, which can no doubt be .
              , classified as the "biggest" ever at
              ] tempted on any stage, while it does
              not crumble the huge beast weighing
              , over G.uOO pounds, it does actually van?
              ish the elephant on the stage in full
              glare of the light, without the use of
              trapa, as the tank of water under the
              Hippodrome r.pron prevents any such
              ' camouflage. Houdini has constructed a
              ; gigantic cylinder shaped container of
              ? such dimensions that the largest cle
              | phant obtainable can enter with ease.
              It walks through this tube and van?
              ishes.'.
              A second new experiment which Mr. .
              i Dillingham will introduce next Mon- j
              | day will be in the final scene of '
              i "Cheer Up!" in the aquatic spectacle,
              where Houdini will present his Sub- i
              ? mcrsible Mystery. In this daring ex
              j hibitioji he is manacled and leg-tied
              i and imprisoned in a heavily weighted
              ! iron bound box, which is lowered into j
              I the tank of water. While submerged :
              ' Houdini accomplishes his escape and j
              j comes to the surface unfettered.
              L Now, to pro-re that he is actually
              j inside the box when it is thrown over
              ; board and that he really takes a risk
              ! and dare3 death in the problem of
              I escaping he will invite members of
              j the audience to nail up the box at I
              j every performance. Ho has further '
              ' obligated himself to the management ?
              to forfeit the sum of $1,000 to any,
              j one-who can prove he is assisted to
              ? escape or that it is possible to breathe ,
              j or that he obtains air when he is '.
              i once submerged. The submerged box,'
              i being filled with holes, is completely
              | filled with water, the audience seeing
              I it all the time, no curtain to obscure
              j the sinking or hide it from view.
              ? .. ?
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1919-12-28/ed-1/seq-34/#words=Houdini+elephant</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              Houdini Is in the Movies
              To Perpetuate His Wotk
              As a Master Magician
              If Harity Houdini were to die tn-mor
              ! row be would pass out content, with the
              ; fullness of life and with the knowledge
              of experiences such as few men have
              bad. lie confessed this quite simply
              as he sat in his study and tinkered
              : with the keys of a typewriter. The
              room had more of the atmosph?re of
              the student than of the magician.
              Houdini, among other things, is a writer
              ' and lover of books. His shelves are
              tilled with rare specimens ?f many
              kinds. His collection of hooks on magic
              is the most extensive in existence.
              The keen, piercing eyes of the magi?
              cian were focussed intently on his audi?
              ence as he told something of his life
              story. The knotted wrists that have
              defied handcuff and manacle and made
              Houdini a universally known figuie lay
              in repose. There was concentration in
              every line of his figure. It is this \fiy
              quality, he says, that has enabled him
              to do unaccountable things.
              "If T were die to-morrow I could
              not complain," said Houdini, "because
              1 have performed every known feat of
              magic from the smallest to the large?.
              The most remarkable thing probably
              was my vanishing elephant, Jenny
              weighing 10,(100 pounds, who used to
              disappear systematically in the Hippo
              drome. My smallest "feat was swallow?
              ing a couple of packages of needles and
              bringing them out threader!.
              "In my opinion Harry Kellar, the
              orginator of the l?vitation wonder,
              Princess Karnac, is the greatest magi?
              cian the world ever saw. This feat is one
              of the classics of wizardry. A* pres?
              ent 1 am writing Eellar's biography.
              There is a different spirit among the
              .magicians of-""to-day. .More of thorn
              are specializing antl they do not zeal?
              ously try to keep their secrets from
              , each other as they did in the old days.
              They are more intent now on improv?
              ing their art than they are on further?
              ing their interests."
              Houilini's discovery of his lock
              breakfng gift dates nack to the time
              of his mother's pies. As a boy in Ap
              pleton, Wis., he wanted to get into the
              1 cupboard where the pastry was' kept,
              but mother had the key, so Harry sim?
              ply manipulated the lock. It cannot
              truthfully be said he realized then that
              he had any special gift in this direc?
              tion. But later, when he worked in a
              machine shop a young man came in
              'Handcuffed. The key had been lost
              and he wanted to free himself. Hou?
              dini struck on a way of releasing him
              and thought nothing more of it until
              he became a magician. Endless the?
              ories have been advanced as to the
              secret of his powers. There are those
              ? who say he slips out. of handcuffs as
              an eel slips through the lingers of an
              amateur fisherman. Others say he ma?
              nipulates cell locks by muscular mag?
              netism. There is a further supposi?
              tion that he squeezes himself through
              bar? of cells. Superstitious persons
              believe lhat spirits help him to escape.
              "I have accomplished everything by
              natural means," said Houdini when
              questioned on this score, "and not en?
              tirely by brawn. Brain work has been
              necessary, and concentration has meant
              more than everything else put together.
              It is the presentation of the trick, and
              not the trick itself that interests me. In
              mystery work I always believe I am the
              person who is talking. No. I don't be?
              lieve in spiritualism at all, nnd 1 think
              the ouija board is nothing more nor
              less than a pleasant pastime. I have
              I traveled ai' over the -ore ?nd
              magic from everj angle It '? ' ? "^
              nating bey?. . b? *,r.
              One and a ht!f '.ear' ?,,? ? ,
              , decided tO go into motion ?n-i,,,. .!"!
              , cause he wanted some ? ? ?J???*
              endure. The next g , .. **'?.?*?
              skeptical and th , ZZt**
              magic handed down to ????m h"
              gerate,] unles ,, -, , , ?g ?ft*
              k???vc???? " ' "??SSW
              ror Island, he . -, Lti""
              into the sea ?n a box with 500 ?~?ril
              of dead weight, go1 ?? . , r th-TL!**-**?
              any visible m6ans of support. ??
              climbs up it. H?
              Houdini sails for England thi? ??i
              to ?iJ?il! a -. ide , ...A?t2 '
              Then lie ii t? ?1??^*
              and during 1921-22 ? ?"g
              world, making a mj i ? ,.,. '.:
              thinks motion pictui . ??.? ?
              derfu! profession in the world W.
              .i i . *-?'*?,? l?~?'.;t?
              then- .i*m for the -v
              voun?-^^^^,
              he intends to I"- p .?? ur ?<,; i ,?.?,?.?'
              To^^?************************-**************1
              Tower B i ?dge n a par
              a theqry that fia?
              of every mot ioi riicl
              thrown on I hi
              Houdini
              t v r t ,v?^^^^^H
              s phy-i
              '?etrior
              He V
              " ?hr?c!ir
              nould r
              ?*?.- - l'ij jr,
              ? ,.
              '1 be.....
              -?*" -?- for ever
              ,:; '? igorous pi j , for eJ*
              one He neit ... .?.,?.
              tl" thinks l g ?- .. ? , f
              did was ?nventii g a d .- suit frM
              v.suce the di ? ?? ca ? -. u. '..
              cape. hV
              did ^_
              dtvt^_
              handing over I -, .;.?
              ernment. Arnoi g ot er ,-- ?S
              vented the and i?
              double-coli^^^^^^^^^Krlbboii. fi.
              Harry Houdini
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86063496/1926-11-02/ed-1/seq-6/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20&words=Harry+Houdini&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=harry+houdini&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              HOUDINI Sons of rabbis have played many parts. Few of them followed the
              ealling of their fathers. There are rabbis’ sons on the vaudeville stage, on
              the legitimate stage, in every walk of life—as is but natural. Remarkable
              it is though that so many rabbis’ sons should have chosen the profession of
              public performer.
              Without doubt Harry Houdini, whose death, all too soon, is now to be
              vecorded at the age of only fifty-two, was perhaps the most distinguished of
              vabbis’ sons who chose the calling of entertaining the public.
              Harry Houdini’s name was Eric Weiss and he was born in Appleton,
              Wis., as the son of Rabbi Weiss. At the age of nine Eric joined a circus.
              This was the beginning of a career which was to make the boy internationally famous. From performing on the trapeze, he aspired to more difficult
              things and in course of time, whilst still in his teens, he was known as “the
              Handcuff King” He could wriggle out of everything. No shackles, no matter how strong, no matter how intricate, could hold him.
              . From being “the Handcuff King,” he extended and elevated the range
              of his performances. From 1885 to 1900 he played all over the country,
              but he could not break into Broadway. New York’s Great White Way
              would have none of him, Houdini was not made of the stuff that yielded.
              If New York would not have him he would try his luck across the seas and
              so to London he went. The experts of Scotland Yard, as the famous English police department is known, handcuffed him. He made his escape, with
              the result that he received a long engagement i the Alhambra, London’s
              noted music hall. From the British capital his fame spread to the Continent of Europe which he toured for six years. His return to his native
              country was a triumph. He had no longer to beg of Broadway to give him
              a hearing or to see fiim. The managers flocked to him.
              From the year 1902 to the day of his untimely death, caused by his
              refusal to break an engagement, Harry Houdini was the acknowledged master magician of the world. America, Europe, Asia, Africa and Australia acclaimed him. By this time, 1908, he had dropped the handcuff tricks and
              electrified his audiences by his more daring and more difficult tasks. There
              were many who essayed to imitate him but they all failed miserably. Houdini could not be imitated. His fertile brain, his mechanical genius, his
              startling discoveries made him unique. There was only one Houdini. And
              so much was this recognized that the Standard Dictionary contains the word
              “houdinize,” meaning “to release or extricate oneself (from confinemeut,
              bonds, or the like) as by wriggling out” A man who gives a new word
              to his native tongue must have to his credit a record of great and notable
              achievements.
              During the last few years Houdini enhanced his international fame
              by exposing fraudulent mediums and all false claims in the field of spirituvalism. For nine consecutive times he was elected president of the Society
              of American Magicians and he was also president of the Magicians’ Club
              of London and a life member of the Authors’ Club of London, for Houdini
              had written a number of books dealing with his art and with spiritualism.
              He was also one of the organizers of the Rabbis’ Sons Association, an organization composed of rabbis’ sons who had made their mark on the stage.
              We have told in brief the life-story of Eric Weiss, or Harry Houdini,
              by which name he will be remembered for all time, because it is an interesting speculation as to what extent his racial strain contributed to his
              phenomenal success. There was the Great Herman, another Jewish magician
              of world-note, and there have been other Jews who excelled in “black magic.”
              It is truly remarkable that this should be the case and it may be explained
              by the sense of the mystic which is part of the Jew’s make-up. This sense
              of the mystic found in Harry Houdini a wonderful outlet in his original and
              inimitable exploits.
              As Jews we pay tribute to the memory of Harry Houdini, grea}est of
              all magicians. He shed luster on the Jewish name in the profession he
              had made his very own and his people have good reason to be prox;iß ;;‘ him
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1925-02-15/ed-1/seq-94/#date1=1756&index=1&rows=20&words=Harry+Houdini&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=harry+houdini&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              Harry Houdini, author, lecturer and magician, giving a special demonstration of spirit trickery for New York toy^ahotms 1
              t 0 jJfmA '
              «p«B^3PXki clergymen. The meeting was held in the Hippodrome. Houdini is devoting a great deal of his time toward «t> r Di*rwood a rnder«-«»Hi -• ... 
              exposing the tricks of alleged spiritualistic mediums who are imposing upon the public
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1952-03-02/ed-1/seq-107/#date1=1756&index=9&rows=20&words=Harry+Houdini&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=harry+houdini&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              After the death of Harry Houdini, the famous magician, this
              JnL letter from an old lady was found among his intimate papers.
              Of all the countless “fan” letters he had received this was the one he
              evidently valued the most and took most pains to preserve.
              And I think he did well. For it is not given to many writers to
              express so movingly the ache of the human heart, nor is it given to
              many artists to receive such a tribute.
              Today’s world is a world of hugeness — of tremendous events in
              all our lives, of large-scale welfare and large-scale disaster. But
              there is still room for the small, kindly things, and we need not call
              ourselves sentimental for clinging to the memory of them, as Houdini
              and his unknown correspondent did, until the end.
              "How did you know I needed a rose?” Perhaps he didn’t. But in
              that chance gesture from the stage, so casual, perhaps in a way so
              accidental and impersonal, there came a contact never to be forgotten — a touch on the nerve of life itself.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1956-03-04/ed-1/seq-122/#date1=1756&index=13&rows=20&words=Harry+Houdini&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=harry+houdini&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1957-09-29/ed-1/seq-165/#date1=1756&index=14&rows=20&words=Harry+Houdini&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=harry+houdini&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1932-11-27/ed-1/seq-76/#date1=1756&sort=relevance&rows=20&words=Harry+Houdini&searchType=basic&sequence=0&index=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=harry+houdini&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=2</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              Y CHARLES J. CARTER.
              ONE
              evening, not so many years ago,
              we were talking, Harry Houdini
              and I. of magic and magicians,
              of superstition and the supernatural. Inevitably, the talk
              turned toward spiritualism and
              the ancient yet ever new belief in human survival after death. Having indulged in much
              good-natured skepticism on this popular subject, Houdini laughingly made me a proposition:
              "If you die first, Charles," he said, "come
              back and give me a sign that there is something after death; and if I am the first to go
              I shall try to return and tell you if there is
              "balm in Gilead.'"
              So It was agTeed that when one or the other
              of us passed on, th» deceased was to tap out
              his initials in the Morse code—four dots or
              tape to signify "H" for Harry; two taps, a
              pause and a tap for "C" in case I preceded
              him. A month or so after the death of
              Houdini I was engaged m constructing
              my bird's-eye maple "spirit cabinet,"
              which had been lying in a storage
              warehouse and had been neglected
              since I had given up performing the
              Davenports' seance trick.
              One bleak December evening I had
              finished working on this abode of
              obliging spirits, whence for many
              years in all lands I had materialized
              Sir William Crooke's favorite ghost,
              "Katie King." About to leave the
              warm theater, preparatory to the
              evening performance, I distinctly
              heard, clear as a Javanese lizard's
              "chocktaw," four sharp knocks on
              my "spirit cabinet."
              I PAUSES) in astonishment; chills
              ran up and down my spine as I
              listened for further sounds. But an
              \qM silent until, remembering the
              agreement. I ran to the cabinet and
              tapped out, fearlessly, two dots, a
              pause, a dot. Then I waited, but in
              vain: I repeated the signal-—but the
              "spirit" of Harry Houdini failed me!
              Returning to my senses, I calmly
              Investigated—and discovered one of
              the panels of the cabinet cracked in
              several, places, thanks to the action
              of steam heat on the sensitive wood,
              reeultiiur in this not auite successful
              message from the beyond. There could just as
              well have been two tape, or three, or a dozen.;
              but the great god Coincidence had arranged for
              exactly four.
              Out of such filmy stuff have men ever made
              their dreams of the supernatural; upon such
              flimsy evidence rests the inexhaustible belief in
              miracles !
              Yet there are profundities both in ancient
              and modern magic which by the layman are not
              easily fathomed: even to many initiates the
              mystic craft, with its confusion of theories, of
              mechanics and phychics, becomes a "mystery"
              —or a ready means of Impressing the gullible,
              •r changing the lead of deception into the substantial gold of personal gain.
              Fraudulent mediumistic activities, such as
              table-tapping, the materialization of spirits,
              spirit-painting, etc., have all been repeatedly
              exposed; every traveler to India expounds his
              individual theory as to how the East Indian
              Yogi sends a boy climbing up an unattached
              rope, only to disappear in mid-air. 
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn78004468/1918-08-02/ed-1/seq-7/#date1=1756&sort=relevance&rows=20&words=Harry+Houdini&searchType=basic&sequence=0&index=8&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=harry+houdini&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=2</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88063294/1944-09-24/ed-1/seq-70/#date1=1756&sort=relevance&rows=20&words=Harry+Houdini&searchType=basic&sequence=0&index=16&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=harry+houdini&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=2</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-daylight-saving</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85038411/1918-03-16/ed-1/seq-15/#words=acting+Acting+Acts+acts+change+changing+clock+clocks+Clocks+daylight+DAYLIGHT+daylight-saving+Hour+hour+hours+Law+law+saved+SAVING+saving+standard+Sun+time+TIME</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              )AYLIGHTSAVING
              TO GIVE WORKERS
              TIME FOR PLAY
              'hysicians Believe Move Will
              Do Much to Better the
              Health of Many
              Men who like the great outdoors.' ho like to leave the offices for a
              alk. a little fishing trip nnd a round .
              f golf?to-day praised the passage
              t the daylight-saving bill by Conress.
              Physicians here to-day also were
              f the opinion that tho new sched- le. to become effective Easter Sunay, will do much for thd healUi fa great number of workers who' or the first time will have a chance
              3 get out into the parks and fields,
              fter a day's work. Businessmen generally tlirough
              out the city this afternoon declared
              that the changing of hours would be accomplished without interrupting or hurting trade. It was said
              that tho change would mean little or nothing to the larger mills ahd
              munitions plants, where three shifts of men now ure engaged in working
              throughout the twenty-four hours, j
              No difficulty will be experienced in
              trolley car schedules, it was said at
              the offices of the Harrisburg and
              'cross-river traction companies and
              the turning of the watch will do
              the trick. ' i
              Theaters, railroads and every business house in the city will operate
              according to the now schedule, and,
              therefore, it was pointed out, there can be 110 confusion after a man
              has once reset his watch.
              Summed up, Mr, Littlefleld says:
              "The bill provides tor an hour
              advance in standard time at 2
              o'clock a. in. on the last Sunday
              in .March of each yefcr and at
              .a. m. the lust Sunday in October
              uie standard time shall be retarded
              one hour. Eleven countries have
              adopted the summer daylight saving plan. The first was Germany, then Great Britain, France, AustriaHungary, Italy, Sweden, Denmark,
              Norway, Holland, Portugal and Au-/
              stralla. London, England, saved
              200,000 tons of coal during a sum- mer. In England in five and onehalf months $12,000,000 in coal '.vere
              saved, and In France $10,000,000. It is estimated that in the United States $10,000,000 can be saved in light
              bills. The hour of daylight con- served by the proposed law can be used by industrial workers throug- out America for gardening and agri- cultural work. This will be a most important gain. We are sure of a great shortage in farm labor this summer and something must be done to offset the probable loss in pro- duction of farm products. The hour saved for daylight every day in April.
              May, June, July, August, September and October will be of inestimable value in stimulating the dwellers in cities and towns to interest them- selves in the production of garden truck
              PASS DAYLIGHT
              SAVING BILL;
              AWAITS WILSON
              Clocks All Over Country Will
              Be Turned Ahead
              One Hour
              Wusliington, Mar. 16—The House
              of Representatives, by 252 to 40. yes
              terday passed the Senate daylight
              saving bill, under the terms of
              which, when it receives the signa
              ture of President Wilson, it'will be
              required that all the clocks in the
              United States be turned ahead one
              hour at 2 a. m. 011 Sunday, March
              31, and remain advanced one hour
              until 2 a. m. on the last Sunday in
              October.
              Under the bill parsed by the
              Senate the limit was, fixed as the
              last Sunday in September. The
              House amendment extending the
              daylight saving one month was
              adopted upon representations by-
              Fuel Administrator Garfield that a
              great amount of l'uel would be con
              served thereby. It is expected that
              the Senate will concur in the amend
              ment to-morrow.
              Five standard time zones for th
              United States will be fixed by the
              Government, according to the bill,
              and it is made mandatory upon the
              railroads to follow the standard
              time.
              By the passage of the bill, tho
              United States joins with England,
              France, Switzerland, Portugal and
              the three Scandinavian countries in
              adopting a method of economy and
              efficiency first taken by Germany
              during the early days of the war.
              Millions of tons .of coal have been
              saved in these countries, it was
              stated to the House to-day by the
              supporters of the measure, by the
              simple means of turning the clock
              ahead over a period of five or six
              months a year.
              England reports a saving of 12,-
              000,000 tons up to date. Several
              Representatives who espoused tha
              bill admitted that when it was first
              proposed they considered it silly.
              But, they said, when they came to
              examine its virtues they fell enthu
              siastically behind it.
              Provided the President signs it,
              and there is little doubt that he will
              do so quickly, the daylight-saving
              bill will have the effect of turning
              us all out of bed an hour earlier
              than we have been accustomed-to
              arise and of sending us back again
              accordingly. The use of fuel at
              night will be conserved by the clos
              ing of establishments at 11 o'clock
              which ordinarily do business until
              12 o'clock. By the clock on the wall
              it will still be 12 o'clock, but by
              the moral conviction it. will be 11.
              Officials of the Chamber of Com
              merce and the Bourse, two of the
              many local organisations which car
              ried the light for the daylight-sav
              ing bill into the very halls of Con
              fess. were jubilant on receipt of
              the news that the legislation was
              so near. Ernest T. Trigg, president
              of the Chamber of Commerce, said:
              "This is very gratifying to us. By
              a readjusting of working hours the
              war industries will be speeded up
              materially and more time for the
              cultivation of war gardens will re
              sult."
              Emil P. Albrecht, president of the
              Bourse, said:
              "This legislation will enable work
              ers to get better results out of their
              daily efforts, as they will be in bet
              ter tune for speeding up operations
              in the early daylight hours of the
              summer months. In such a large
              manufacturing center as Philadel
              phia the gain in efficiency in the
              various war work lines will be tre
              mendous. Only on Monday last the
              directors of the Bourse urged upon
              Congress for the second time within
              two months the necessity for this
              change."
              TO SPEAK AT Y. M. C. A.
              Prof. Charles Calvert Ellis, of
              Juniata College, will be the speaker
              at the men's mass meeting to be held
              in Falinestock Hall, Sunday after
              noon. His subject will be "Does It
              Pay to Be Good'.'" Special music will
              be given and an interesting program
              is being arranged for the meetinK
              which is to be held under the aus
              pices of the Central Y. M. C. A.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045433/1918-03-16/ed-1/seq-1/#words=act+change+Changed+changed+changes+Clock+clock+clocks+Clocks+daylight+DAYLIGHT+Daylight+daylight-saving+HOUR+Hour+hour+Hours+HOURS+hours+law+saving+SAVING+Saving+Standard+standard+time+times</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              DAYLIGHT SAVING TIMl
              3HOURS
              VASTED
              - lYLJGHT
              r" I'nY
              8HOUR WORKDAY
              FREE
              LIGHT
              HOURS
              ?
              ItlGHI
              These charts show vividly how the daylight saving plan will give j
              everybody more "free hour#" of daylight. You've heard this: "Well,!
              there are just so many hours of daylight in a day and you can't change j
              'em." But wait?the daylight hours before your work-day itarts are
              so-called "wasted hours"?you ?leep them away or spend them getting
              ready to go to work. The daylight saving plan merely "shifts" an
              hour of daylight to the "free hours" after work, when you can use it.
              The tables is based on the average June day and the workday from
              8 to 5 includes an hour for lunch.
              Moving the Clock.
              The clock will be set forward one
              hour at 2 a. m., March SI, according
              to the House bill. At the same hour
              on October 27, the clock will be set
              back.
              The present standard time rones
              will remain in effect.
              Both changes will take place on
              Sunday mornings so that the least
              possible wrench may be given to
              the industrial fabric of the nation.
              But even at that on the railroads
              alone there will be some 1.000 pas
              senger trains and 5.000 trains run
              ning on the tracks when the change
              comes, and 1,698.SIS railroad clocks
              and watches must be set forward
              to keep traffic moving and prevent j together. At present In summer
              accidents. In 1883. however, a sim- j London closes as New York opens,
              ilar change from local to standard i More time for golf, amateur base
              time went into effect on 100,000 ball and tennis.
              miles of railroad without a single
              mishap.
              Benefits of Plan.
              The following benefits will be
              reaped by the daylight-saving plan:
              Saving of one to one and a half
              million tons of coal per year, ac
              cording to Fuel Administration es
              timates.
              Increased food production by sub
              urban gardeners.
              Less traffic accidents.
              Improvement in health of all the
              people. More fresh air. Women
              workers will return from work in
              daylight.
              Speeding up of freight transpor
              tation by giving extra hour at docks
              and terminals.
              New York and London Stock Ex
              changes will be open for one ho'
              :i;
              Nation Moves Clocks Up
              One Hour Easter Sunday
              Daylight Saving Bill Passes House by Big Ma
              jority as War Measure?Some Opposition
              from Farming Communities.
              Clocks all over the oountry will
              be set ahead one hour, beginning
              March 31, under the so-called day
              light-saving bill, pessed yesterday by
              the House, 252 to 40.
              Senator Calder, author of the
              ure In the upp?r braftch iftf Congress,
              said the House amendments would
              be agreed to, so that a conference
              would not be necessary.
              Provisions of Bill.
              The bill provides that at 2 o'clock
              p. m. on the last Sunday In March
              each year, clocks all over the country
              which affect any operations of the
              Federal government, or railroads,
              i shall be set ahead one hour. At 2
              j o'clock p. m., the last Sunday in Oc
              j tober of each year, they are to be
              i retarded one hour.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030431/1918-03-24/ed-1/seq-58/#words=act+change+clock+clocks+Daylight+daylight+hour+hours+Law+saving+Saving+sun+time</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              Daylight Saving Is Simplicity Itself
              How Ben Franklin s Idea Conceived in 1784, Just Made Into Law Here, Will Affect
              Folks After Easter and Save Millions to the Nation
              10
              By WM. ARCHIBALD FERGUSON,
              Secretary of the National Daylight Sar
              ins Association.
              ON Ihc coming Apwl 1 more people
              in the United Slates will probably
              be April fool vietims than on any previ
              ous or future April 1, for Congress lias
              decreed that at 2 o'clock on the morning
              of March 31 the hands of the clock shall
              be turned forward one hour; in other
              words, the United States will then begin
              to live under the davlight saving plan,
              and doubtless thousands will forget to
              make the change.
              Every individual who is wise Jind hates
              to be fooled will before retiring on the
              evening prior to Kaster Sunday, March
              31, see to it that not onh his watch but
              every clock in the bou.se is turned for
              ward one hour. Otherwise on Sunday he
              will find the Easter services half over be
              fore he arrives at the church, and on
              Monday morning, April 1, VMS, rising
              an hour late, if he is a commuter he will
              miss his morning train by an hour and
              be greeted at the factory or office with
              such remarks as "April fool!" "You day
              light blacker! You forgot to turn your
              watch ahead, eh 7'' and all day long he
              will be the butt of many jokes.
              May Wait Lone for Dinner.
              If lie starts for home at the tame hour '
              as usual and has not during the day tele
              phoned his wife to turn the clock ahead
              be will have a long wail tor dinner. One
              thing Is certain, hotvivcr. that before he
              retires that night crry member of his
              household will know that the daylight pav
              ing plan is in effect and that the people
              of the United States are living an hour
              ahead of sun time.
              The daylight sating idea U almost as
              Id as the United States it-elf and our
              country can rightly claim the credit for
              all the many advantages which will act-rue
              from it, not only in this country bat also
              in those countries which anticipated the
              United Slates in its adoption, for it was
              Benjamin Pranklm who Iirst conceited
              the idea.
              On an early morning walk along the
              Etreels of Imdou in 17.S4 the thought Iirst
              came to him, and in passing if on to the
              world at large he said:
              ''In a walk through the Strand and Tit et
              ttrect one morning at 7 o'clock I ob.-Ttcd
              then; was not one shop open, although
              it had been davlight ami the sun up
              above three hours, the inhabitants of
              lxndon choo.-iug voluntarily to live by
              candle light and sleei by sun-bine; and
              yet often complaining :t little absurdly of
              the dnty on candles and the high price
              of tallow.''
              Soon thereafter in the Jtwrnal Je
              Faris he publL-hcd an article, later ap
              pearing among his es-ays under the title
              4An Economical Project," which further
              elaborated the advantages of daylight sav
              ing; namely, of "Turning the clock for
              ward an hour" so that everybody would
              live one hour longer by davlight and one
              hour less by artificial light.
              Beaten Repeatedly in Britain.
              Tor many years in England in the
              last century Sir William Willctt annually
              introduced his davlight sating bill in Par
              liament and annually the bill wa- de
              feated amid laughter and ridicule.
              In 1915 Germany tirst adopted the plan
              to speed np the war production and io
              benefit by the tremendous saving in fuel
              consumption. France and England and
              nil other European countries except Rus
              sia soon alter followed her example.
              Since its adoption in Europe, the.
              United State.-, Canada and Mexico have
              been out of harmony, so far as time was
              concerned, with European countries, to
              their loss not only in business, for the
              stock exchanges of Ixindon and Paris un
              der the new plan were closed before the
              exchanges of New York and I tost on were
              open, but also as regards the tremendous
              savings pos-ible in light bills, which, it
              is estimated, annually will run from V0,
              000,000 to $50,000,000 in the United
              Sfates alone.
              The plan has been ardently advocated
              in this country since May, Wlfi, by the
              Merchants Association of this city, cham
              bers of commerce of Boston, Rochester,
              Philadelphia, Chicago and Pittsburg, the
              United States Chamber of Commerce,
              Washington, D. C, and the National Day
              light Saving Association, of which Marcus
              M. Marks, former Borough President of
              Manhattan, is the president. Mr. Marks
              has often been called the '"'father of day
              light saving in this country."
              To illustrate the effect of the. plan, let
              us follow Jack Hurryup, a New York
              commuter, through his first business day
              under the new regime.
              Mr. Hurryup is a habitual reader of
              The Scn, and accordingly he knows he
              should on the evening of March 30 turn
              his watch and clocks ahrad one hour be
              fore he retires at 9 o'clock. But on the
              night of Easter Sunday he goes through
              the house from the kitchen to the
              roof and advances each clock one hour
              and is surprised when he arritis iu his
              bed chamber and looks at his watch to
              lind that he is retiring at 10:1.1 instead
              of i:15 his lirst shock from daylight
              saving.
              The alarm dock rings louder than
              usual the next morning and he. jumps out
              that several of his friends to whom he
              telephones have not yet arrived at the
              office, but are expected auy minntt.
              At 1 o'clock, his usual hour, he hurries
              to the restaurant for luncheon and finds
              a slim crowd. Upon returning to the of
              fice all is running smoothly and at quar
              ter of 5 he closes his desk to catch the
              5:15. As he passes through the gate at
              the Grand Central he sees the same fa
              miliar crowd starting on their nightly
              journey home.
              Ed, Kill and Dick are on hand for the
              nightly game of poker, .lack and his
              friend Ed were the losers in the game,
              for they spent most of their time joking
              Bill and Dick for being April fools aud
              having missed the train in the morning.
              Alighting from the commuters' special
              in the country, he is happily pleased to
              note that it has not vet begun to grow
              BENJAMIN FRANKLIN
              jr FROM THE ENGRAVING OF THE DUPLESSIS' PORTRAIT OF 1778
              Noted American philosopher is the father of daylight saving.
              of bed at C:.'J0, leans out of the window
              and noles that the sun is ju-t ri-ing, and
              then realizes that he is really getting up
              one hour earlier by the sun, although the
              alarm went off at the usual hour.
              He rushes through his bath and his
              breakfast and runs for the train. When
              he arrives at the station he is surprised to
              find many of his pals missing. The train
              pulls in and he runs to his customary scat
              in the smoker: the table and the cards
              are there, but only one plajcr besides
              himself. He greets Ed .(ones, who
              boarded the train at the station, above
              with:
              "Good April fool joke on Bill and
              Dick! Guess they forgot to turn their
              watches ahead last night. We'll have
              some sport with them to-morrow."
              Mr. Hurryup piles into the subway
              aud is astonished to lind a seat at the
              Grand Central, his second shock from
              the daylight saving. "Guess a lot of peo
              ple are fooled by this daylight saving
              this morning," he mutters to himself.
              He arrives at the office, looks at the
              clock to see whether he has consumed the
              usual time on his journey down town and
              is surprised to find that he is arriving
              at 8:1.1, the exact time at which he took
              the tram at his station. Shock No. 3.
              No oflice boy in sight. He rings for his
              stenographer and she greets him with a
              hearty "Good morning !" He tells her
              to get the porter immediately and turn
              that oflice clock ahead one hour.
              He finds no mail on his desk and con
              cludes that the letter carrier is also one of
              the daylight saving April fo;Is.
              The morning runs on as usual except
              dark and that the sun is still shining
              brightly at 0 o'clock. "We fooled ton to
              day. Old Sol, and will keep fooling you
              until November 1," he says to himself.
              Arriving at the house he goes to the
              cellar, and finding that he need not turn
              on the lights he gels out the lawn mower
              and bis garden tools.
              "This daylight sating is all right," he
              calls up fo Mary; ''don't hurry to get on
              the dinner. I am going to mow the lawn
              and wotk in the garden until sundown."
              " After an hour's work about the grounds
              .lack comes in to dinner and he anil Mary
              agree that daylight saving is the greatest
              boon ever conferred upon New York com
              muters. The chief benefits of the plan, as
              proved by the experience of England,
              France and other European countries
              where it has been in force, may be gen
              erally summarized under three heads:
              Eirst General health of all people
              benefited by reason of an added hour of
              daylight in the late afternoon, which has
              been and will be u-ed for outdoor recre
              ation and exercise.
              Second Increased production of food
              stuffs through the stimulating cultivation
              of home gardening.
              Third Money saved in lighting bills:
              each householder will burn artificial light
              one hour less each day, provided, of
              course, he continues his usual habits of
              retiring at night.
              The report of the summertime commit
              tee appointed by the British Parliament
              in September, 1!1G, to inquire into the
              social and economic results of the sum
              mertime act shows that the extra hour of
              dat light was generally ucd for the pur-po-e
              of outdoor recreation and pursuit's,
              and, in particular, for the cultivation of
              home gardening.
              The athletic dubs reported that the
              cricketers, bowlers, golfers and tennii
              players took full advantage of the extra
              hour of light, and swimming pools and
              playgrounds were utilized to full capac
              ity. Iu view of the national agitation last
              year, which is being renewed now, for
              the cultivation of home gardens to in
              crease the production of food the inaugu
              ration of the daylight saving plan iu this
              country will undoubtedly very greatly
              stimulate home gardening, particularly in
              the neighborhood of the great cities. In
              New York city alone there are 1,000.000
              daily commuters. Should only one-half
              of them use the extra hour of daylight
              which the plan will give in cultivating
              home gardens there will bo 3,000,000 extra
              hours utilized weekly in gardening and
              during the seven summer months in which
              the plan is in operation 2,000,000 days of
              extra work and time will be spent by
              these 500,000 commuters in the cultiva
              tion of gardens.
              What It Means in Potatoes.
              It has been estimated that if the av
              erage commuter wpre to work a plot of
              land only 20x-10 feet, which would le
              about I-50lh of an acre, and planted it all
              to potatoes, on the basis of 300 bushels
              per acre each commuter would he able
              to rai-e from four to live bushels of pota
              toes; on this basis half of the commuters
              of New York city would add to the potato
              crop during 191S approximately 2,500,
              0011 bushels.
              The saving in lighting bills ami in fuel
              u.-ed for producing electricity and gas
              wdl be tremendous. Public Service En
              gineer Robert L. Bruuct of Providence,
              If. I., has carefully estimated this saving
              and fixed the amount during the period of
              live mouths, which the plan originally
              contemplated, at $-10,000,000, and tiie
              amount of coal sated at 1,000,000 tons.
              This sating will he unitersal as every
              hou-eholder will u-e one hour les- of aili
              licial light daily under the new plan.
              Other additional benefits will be the re
              duction of traffic accidents due to Ici-cncd
              tran-poriation of pa'.sengers under arti
              ficial light, reduction of the danger of eye
              strain on account of the lessened amount
              of reading and work done under artiticial
              light and more lime for open air military
              drilling.
              The davlight sating hill as signed by
              President Wilson on March 19 provides
              lhat the plan shall go into effect at 2
              o'clock antemeridian time on Sunday
              morning, March 31, at which time clocks
              and watches, probably upon a signal
              flashed from the United States Naval
              Observatory at Washington will be
              turned ahead one hour. Comparatively
              very few individuals, unless by design,
              will be conscious w hen the change is
              made. "This hour was selected by reason
              of the fact that at 2 o'clock in the morn
              ing the number of railroad trains actually
              en route is smallest,
              Nobody Will Be Inconvenienced.
              Nobody will be seriously inconte
              ilienced, unless on Easter Sunday morn
              ing or on the night previous individuals
              forget to turn their clocks and watches
              forward an hour, as the result of which
              omission they may find at some time dur
              ing that daj- that they arc one hour be
              hind the rest of the country.
              The remarkable thing about the effect
              of the movement is that practically no
              class of business will be injured; the only
              exception is the open air moving picture
              exhibitors-, who under the new plan will
              be. unable on account of the sun's setting
              an hour later to begin their performance
              as early as they have been accustomed in
              previous years, which may result in a
              loss of patronage. The ordinary business
              man, as far as bis business is concerned,
              will not be affected in the slightest, ex
              cept that he will be more often tempted
              this summer to go to the baseball game
              which will begin at -1:30 o'clock instead
              of 3:30 and to run down more often to
              the beaches for a dip before dinner.
              Everybody under the new regime will
              continue his old habits rising, working,
              dining and retiring at the same hours;
              we will still live by the clocks and give
              the laugh to the cob.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88064305/1918-03-28/ed-1/seq-1/#words=acting+change+clock+Daylight+hour+Law+law+Saving+Sun+time+timepiece</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              Daylight Saving is
              Law Of Land.
              r- Don't make any dates for 2:30
              t, Sunday st cause morning, March 31, be. there ain't gonna be no
              ill sich animal. In fact, there will
              le beno 2 o'clock. At 60 seconds
              le after 1:59 it will not be 2 o'clock
              but 3 o'clock. Similarly, if you
              contemplate any sort of engagement, business or social, for 1:30
              Sunday morning Oct. 27, you
              g had better make plain which
              v "1:30" you mean, because there
              n is going to be two of 'em on that
              y day. Exactly 60 seconds after
              1:59 a. m. Sunday morning, Oct.
              27, it will not be 2 o'olook, but
              1 o'clock again.
              That is what President Wils'i
              n did Tuesday, March 19, when he
              n affixed his signature to the daylight bill which had already been
              passed by congress. As a result,
              the d that Muniversally life is growing accepted more plaint complex every day, has another supporting argument.
              However there is going to be
              very little confusion, after all.
              Just remember to do this, and
              you'll be all right:
              Before you go to bed on the
              night of Saturday, March 30, set
              every watch, alarm clock, grand.
              father's clock, cuckoo clock or
              other timepiece in the entire
              house, one hour ahead.' This is
              going be done in every household in the entire United States.
              On the morning of Sunday, March
              31 when you awake, the change
              will have been accomplished.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1918-03-30/ed-1/seq-2/#words=change+CLOCK+clock+clocks+daylight+daylight-saving+Hour+hour+HOUR+hours+saving+savings+sun+time+times</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              If you do so understand the daylight-saving- law, and there are many
              who are puzzled, do .not worry. Just
              before going- -
              to bed tonight advance
              your clock one hour that Is. make
              It an hour fast and then forget It--
              about 'your business as usual.
              You will notice no difference or
              change, except that, the sun will rise
              later and will set later. The even
              ings will be an hour longer.
              Under the Jaw. all of the clocks of
              the nation must be. advanced one 'hour
              at ' 2 o'clock' tomorrow morning--.
              There, is. no need' of staying, up until
              2 o'clock, however: you can turn the
              clock up Just aa well before, going to
              bed.
              Here's a lip.
              If perchance you are prone to stay
              out late Saturday night be sure and
              tell wlfey the time' when you come
              in. before the clocks are turned up,
              otherwise you will be an hour worse
              off. 'for official time will akip from
              2 to 3 o'clock in an Instant tomorrow
              morning--.
              ,If you fail- to advance jrour docks
              and, watches on hour before, going to
              bed tonight .you will be an hour behind .the country and everybody else
              tomorrow. Tou will get to Sunday
              school or church an hour late, and
              your meals will be off schedule. If
              you do not realise this Sunday, you
              will be on hour late getting- to work
              Monday morning.
              Those who have to work on Satur- -
              irfllVprVrMWMV
              the matter daylight saving, which begin tomorrow.
              All you have do when you bed tonight,
              your clock hour ahead. Get the regular time,
              BY THE CLOCK, and proceed usuaL The simplest
              statement the whole thing the clock hour
              ahead and follow the clock.
              HaYe7f aDatefor
              2:30 Ton new Mora?
              BetYouDon'tKeepIt
              o'clock,
              morning,'
              another Tlmea
              today.--
              either."
              "Why,
              certainly
              "Wrong--. Archie. Follow
              closely. There
              morning. When daylight
              savings effect
              o'clock hands
              moved around
              o'clock.
              nights night,
              Jnmp'
              o'clock.
              night hour's
              usual, unless
              earlier
              clocks
              for live ,?,.
              Jbr .
              for
              for
              jC,-0,-. , W lv '. . ?..,. .4 -,.
              of
              to is go to set
              oxK up at
              as
              of is set arc
              -
              Til meet you at 2:30
              in the said one man
              to in front of Tho
              Tes No you won't
              you --poor fish. You can
              be there at 2:S0.
              to
              will be no 2JO in
              the the
              law goes into at
              2 the on the clock:
              will "be one hour to
              3 So there will be no
              ha'.." past two." l
              --Welt I'll be !
              day will ,jct 'a short as
              the' clock will from 2 to 3
              Sleep Henr Less.
              If you do not have to work to
              you will get an less
              sleep than you go to
              bed an hour than usual to
              make up for' the hour the will
              skip. If you turn up the clock an
              w "?'
              hour before) to bed and then go
              to bed you wlti get the
              usual night's sleep. For If
              the usual bedtime is 11 o'clock, turn
              the clock up one hour at 10 from 10
              to 11 and go. to bed. The only'
              necessary change for you then
              the saving- law has been I
              made, and you have wor- -l
              ries.
              The. Sunday
              will- have to speed up tomorrow !
              momlnsr. as will the milkman anA
              other early hour to
              up for the hour that skips away at
              2 o'clock. The will have!
              to get an early start for press times
              after 2. o'clock.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87057262/1918-03-30/ed-1/seq-7/#words=change+changed+changes+clock+CLOCK+clocks+daylight+Hour+hour+hours+saving+savings+TIME+time+timepiece+timepieces</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              TURN THE CLOCK
              AHEAD TONIGHT
              Just Do Thle When You Go to Bed
              Tonight and Then Forget to
              Worry About Ttiat Ad
              ditional Hour.
              GIVES YOU MORE TIME
              If You Play Golf Just Think of the
              Extra Daylight You'll Have to
              Chase Over the
              Green.
              JUST DO THIS AND BE CONTENT.
              8et all clocks and timepieces ahead
              One hour Just before retiring Saturday
              night.
              Those who are awake at 2 a. m.,
              Sunday, may wait until that hour to
              set their timepieces ahead one hour.
              Ahead—-forward—one hour. Under
              stand this and do it, and having done
              it, be content, nor worry any more
              about it.
              This simple Instruction, obeyed so
              thoroughly that every timepiece in
              the oountry la thus changed one hour
              ahead, will carry out the law and pre
              vent any confusion whatever. Every
              phase of life will move ahead with the
              cloaks—trains, street cars, business,
              religious services—everything. The 9
              o'clock trains Sunday morning will
              leave at 9 o'clock by the clock. The 7
              o'clock atreet cars will run at 7 o'clock
              by the clock—everything will be Juet I
              as it Is now, by the clock. And the riotic
              clock will be the only thing to rely on
              as
              It Is now. Just what!his
              the clock says, after It has been turned
              ahead one hour, that will be the time,
              and the time for everything, Just as It
              is now. There will be no change in
              anything except the clocks and
              watches, and no one need pay any at
              tention to the fact that they have been
              moved one hour ahead.
              Complete plans for the daylight sav
              ing system, which' goes into effect to
              morrow have been announced by fed
              eral officials and the nation's workers
              are ready to push the hands of the
              •clock one hour ahead to assist Uncle
              Sam In hig fight for liberty.
              Every city in the country, every
              town and village, everything is in
              readiness for the new system, a sys
              tem that will save the nation thou
              sands of tons of coal daily as well as
              assisting the working man, the shop
              girl and the laboring clasa as well as
              the busy office man.
              What this plan means to the nation
              can be described in a few words. In
              the first place It means the conserva
              tion of the fuel supply. Secondly,-it
              gives the average man more time to
              devote to gardening, which In turn
              means a "bigger supply of food for the
              nation and, thirdly, it means a more
              healthy nation.
              The work of the masses will be done
              In daylight, where, heretofore, it was
              done In the dark a certain number of
              hours a day.
              Favored by All.
              Since the plan was first spoken of
              it has attracted the attention of some
              of the biggest men in the country.
              Efficiency experts have studied the
              plans and in very instance have re
              turned a favorable report on their
              study.
              The action has been favored by
              President Wilson for the past several
              months. Garfield and Hoover have
              been ardent supporters of the plan.
              There has never been an argument
              against the system and every learned
              man in the country is of the J.rsllef that
              the plan will greatly aid the nation's
              savings.
              The daylight saving plan will give
              the following daily advantages:
              One hour or more for outdoor rec
              reation. Recreation is a national as
              set, an immense force for health and
              moral well-being.
              Working mothers and fathers obtain
              an extra hour for outdoor play with
              their children, both summer and win
              ter.
              One hour less for bad lights in tene
              ments.
              Lessened eyestrain for workers and
              school children due to the use of artifi
              cial light.
              Smaller risk of accident in indus
              trial establishments, because there
              jwill he a light hour instead of a dark
              one at the end of the working day at
              ,tlie time of greatest fati-gue and most
              {frequent accidents.
              Lessened risk of accidents due to
              I transportation and traffic conditions,
              because the afternoon rush will fall in
              iduylight Instead of darkness,
              Working girls will be on the way
              home in the daylight instead of in the
              !dark in winter.
              Our last hour of sleep will be sound
              ier and more 'beneficial than it is un
              der present conditions, because there
              will be less light.
              General efficiency will, of course, be
              •increased by any improvement in the
              (health morals and social welfare of
              tiie workers and others.
              Morning Coolness.
              I In summer a cool hour In the morn
              jing is substituted for a hot one In
              I the afternoon.
              I In winter a light hour at the end of
              the day is substituted for a dark one.
              This is especially valuable com^g as
              it does at the time of greatest fatigue,
              and is peculiarly valuable in some in
              dustries where aocurate eyesight is
              essential.
              Efficiency is lowest in the later aft
              ernoon, the time when- accidents are
              roost frequent.
              There will be the greatest of all sav
              ings—that of hnman materials, as
              pointed out above.
              Immediate saving in form of reduc
              tion of expense for light and heat.
              Ultimate saving in the conservation
              QPHE DAILY GATE CITY^
              of coal and other sources of light and
              heat
              Possilble reduction in the cost of liv^
              ing of those who like to work in their
              gardens, utilizing the extra outdoor
              hour for this purpose.
              A memorandum containing the fol
              lowing important reasons tor the uni
              versal adoption of the daylight saving
              plan, looking at the matter from the
              standpoint of war needs, was sent to
              the house committee in February:
              The training of the national forces
              will be expedited, and the practice of
              home guards and similar organiza
              tions, the members of which have oth
              er regular occupations, will be great
              ly facilitated.
              The production in all
              I
              plant3
              Are Asked to Cover up Bargains If
              It is Necessary to Dis
              play Posters for Liberty
              Bond Campaign.
              A
              large assortment of posters ad
              vertising the third Liberty loan has
              been sent to all township chairmen,
              by County Chairman Dunlap, for use
              in stores and windows everywhere.
              The supply for Keokuk will be dis
              tributed, probably by boy scouts,
              throughout the business district and
              it is hoped that merchants will give
              them a very prominent position in
              their windows, as the way to help can
              the kaiser.
              Some of these posters are works ot
              the highest art, and some arevnot so
              artistic. Some are in black and white
              and some are in colors. All of them
              are attractive and have a lot of force
              of appeal in them.
              "These posters were not designee!
              to harmonize with the color scheme of
              the milinery or the hardware in the
              store windows," said Chairmfen
              windows, even if they do hide some
              mighty good bargains in spring styles
              jor some goods formerly eight dollars
              and now down to ninety-eight cents.
              Raising three billion dollars to win
              the war Is not exactly a matter of do
              ing things conveniently, you know."
              Tax Slackers.
              St. Paul Pioneer Press: Collectors
              -fniSrternal
              revfnue.alln0Unce th^
              ,'^Wr
              GATE
              which
              ore making materials for war use, in
              creased, and the conditions of work
              for their employes would be improved.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1918-03-30/ed-1/seq-3/#words=act+change+clock+Clocks+clocks+DAYLIGHT+HOUR+hour+hours+laws+SAVE+standard+time+timepiece+times</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              Clocks to Be Turned Ahead at
              2 A. M. To-Morrow With
              Elaborate Ceremony.
              The programme is complets to-dsy
              for welcoming Amerlcs's first twenty-three.
              hour day with due dignity
              and ceremony. New York, which
              originated tha daylight aavlng move
              ment. will lead in the celebration.
              All clocks are to be puahed ahead
              one hour to-morrow morning. Tke
              hour from 2 lo J will he dropped, cut
              out as effectively aa If II never were.
              Thus I. ister Sunday becomes the
              llrst twenty-three-hour day In United
              Statea history.
              The most ceremonious observance
              will be that at specially Illuminated
              Madison 8iinre I'ark. The Police
              Band and the Manhattan Borough
              Hand will play and the Community
              Chorus sing from midnight until I
              A. M . which will be but two hours.
              President Wilson has delegated Mar
              cus M. Marks, a pioneer In the day
              light saving move, to turn the hands
              of the four great Metropolitan tower
              clo ks. There Is also to be u formal
              celebration at Brooklyn borough Hall
              Most clocks In the country will be
              set Sktad before the legal time
              change. Hanks, ofllc. s, etorcs apd
              factorlea will make the change be
              fore they close this afternoon and
              to-night. In homea the clock will ks
              moved ahend when tha family retlrss.
              Hut thousands are going to stay up
              to lake part In the cercmonlee. In
              some pl.icea the cbango will be made
              with the solemnity of h rile. New
              Yorkers want to see what It Is like
              to lose a wholn hour of time, espe
              cially those who sr In the habit
              of crowding all they can Into tha nor
              mal day. Uut It Is all to be very simple.
              You simply put the clock ahead an
              hour and forget about It for at
              months. Then, by a reverse ehlft.
              you'll get the hour back.
              Whllo Mr Marke la turning ahead
              Iho groat banda of Iba clock on the
              Metropolitan Tower, by electrical de
              vlcea In the directors' room of the
              building, t;nlted Htates Senator Will
              iam M ('alder, who fought for the
              bill In Congress, will perform a sim
              ilar ceremony In Brooklyn, where he
              will shove uhead one hour the hands
              of the City Hall clock.
              AI 2 o'clock sharp to-morrow morn
              ing the alarm system of the Interbor-
              nejjrn w ill signal all trainmasters, des-
              putcners and station agents on tb
              subway t" advance their watches and
              clocks nn hour.
              In thousands of cities and hamlets.
              In fact, every town that Is lurgo
              enough to boast of a timepiece In ISM)
              public square, similar petty robbenesi
              will lie committed on the old Man
              with the Scythe In Hie hope that tbo
              collected bOUTS so saved will add an
              hour In thS morning and another lb
              the evening with which lo work fo,
              tlie salvation of civilization to pro
              dues tha mate rlabi nscasaury tor tho
              Alio s on the lighting front.
              Kroin tne Hat dweller in the nron
              BfkS will stoal tho hour from his tin
              alarm Block on the cnair beside his
              bed to Hie man on KifUi Aicnuo
              whose soft footed butler will change
              i the bunds of the uristocratlc grand
              father clock In the corner on the
              I stairs, all will obseive the slmpl'i
              I ceremony, not because It Li a cere
              I mony, but because the welfare of tbo
              I Nation demands it.
              All railroad employees and marine
              nun on duty to-morrow at 2 A.
              will simply lake out their watches
              ,.nd push i io in uhead -no hour Offi
              cials huvo arranged achedulea to con
              form to the change No trains are
              scheduled to lea. New York between
              ; and 3 A M to-morrow, so no con
              fusion will arise. Milkmen may be
              a little late because milk trains ma
              no) have gained the lost hour by
              dnwn lo-morrow.
              It Is estimated the added hour of
              layllghl win save Ili'.x),ono In money
              and l.isai.ooo tons of ooal, It will also
              add W the Nation's food supply by
              giving garden, os Hie i ntra hour.
              All the churches have urranged t
              Conform to tlie new schedule, which
              i. in ilns In effect until Oct. SI.
              CANADA TO SAVE DAYLIGHT.
              ties. lire like lulled states' tu Me
              I'aaaed un.
              OTTAWA. Oat., March 10 The
              Canadian Havitght saving nin. t-
              rsspondlng to the measure which be
              Comas effestlve In the t'nlied tttatea
              lo-morrow, will i i-.i.- be paaaed
              in about a fortnight When the
              Senate resumes in April ft. daylight
              ssvlng will be the first Important
              legislation before It
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1918-03-31/ed-1/seq-8/#words=change+Clock+clock+CLOCK+clocks+daylight+Daylight+daylight-saving+hour+HOURS+hours+save+saving+Saving+Sun+sun+Time+time+time-pieces+timely+timepiece+TIMES</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
                      ASTER CLOCK AT
              OBSERVATORY NOT
              TOBE.SHIEAD
              At --It o'clock' this morning, the
              TfjiFferf States Naval Observatory will
              flash otfer America the first "artificial noon" signal in the history of
              the nation. '." To'all Intents and 'purposes; the
              tTme of th "nashsCJrjjoel-riotf,- -
              ln
              accordance with the inaadatr
              . gresa which" ordered 1 all official
              "
              clocks' move a forward one.,hour at 2
              o'clock 4hls, moraine, but out on
              Georgetown Heights, at the Naval
              Observatory. It will still bo 11. a. m.
              meridian time by the uaJtlWa standard"
              k
              clock. '
              .The Xaval Observatbrr. It was slid
              today, will probably be the l
              "spot on the American, map. where
              trie master clock wll continue running, according ,to true time, and
              on'e. hour behind the rest
              of tiie country. The answer to this
              apparent; indifference tff the orders of
              Congress lle 1nt&e.Jle.iJeaT;e adjustment of Amricjt;rUndrd tlrrfe-plet me enrorjoryTper.ifp5g dayy supplies the pojnOnentCjia 'Atoerlcan
              ships far at. jsja'wlth'' ihe.ytandara
              Urn, or the'Werfdlan not Washington.
              LleuU JU --Patton,, . NU and
              Time .Kspert "8iuct"tlie Observa- -
              iqry,--
              .under the old ByJm-atJl- O' o'clock la". night. ThlattlmaVltiab'-- neae'frated tn
              efery PJ(rtJgr-v-eijtou- nty over glgantlo-- ntrvyte3 of telegraph
              wires aba IfevfrM fift-flaahed' East:
              V.est. North, and Booth by-- wireless
              fronvtht: Arlington rad)6tat!ob.
              Ordlh'arrlly", the Obr.vatory. aends
              out but-o- tlrae-aii- a.,dy. That
              IsrrvenLat-QOon- , Xwdjlsthes. (bough,
              were sent oufc yesterday one at soon
              .and- the'Bthr 'ajklO. 1 ra, Thelast 'flash wj((jspf flnal- warning! to
              , get vbrymUtJinity'lbior turning thejn VsS&Sfc,1.'?.. Alttrbngh. Congress- t 2 a.,m. as
              o mjtf.he.-3JeW- daylight-savin- g
              plan inu&i'cperatton, comparatively- .fevfjsUjcKs. were, turned- - up ,at
              that hour. Host of the mantleplecfc
              chronometers and family alarm
              flocks got their '
              turning-ti- p, mV bedtime, last night, and, America, for .the
              most partj.awDlie-- this Paaday-- morning In accordance- with the new
              schedule
              Pome hour had o be set. however,
              'for; the' use' of railways and other Industries where lime is always,an .Important factor, and the wee sma,'
              hours of this morning were' chosen
              by .Congress ..because, less, .confusion
              was liable to result from a change
              at that Jjour, when traffic, Is compara-timel- y
              quiet and--
              the world- - alee. than at any other hour of the whole
              twe"hty-fou- r.
              Tie. average tune-piec- e, no matter I
              how excellent and It may
              be. can be turned up one hour by hand
              wiuwui iipw ounw w iu wra. -
              some one eVen touch the liands of the 1
              bjjc jtn4ter clock at th XavakObeerva-'tor- y
              and" .the observa.tory scientists 'urobably'vIH have to' stay up' alt --Sight
              looking for the trouble. Those observatory clocks are looped up with a most
              amazing tangle of electric wires, and
              turning them forward an hour Is a, task
              t
              that wotihi reejnlre days,"of effort, because 4h Job would .have to be done by
              electricity and by very slow, 'degrees:
              For that reason, the JS'tTal Observa
              tory will ran '
              its clocks according to I
              stellar time aO "during the present, artl
              flqial-tim- e period.- - and in that way
              , any possible maladjustment of these
              'dejlcate, temperame
              Text ofDaylightSaving Law
              An act to save daylight and to provide, standard time for the United
              Be it enacted by the Senate and House of
              United' States of America m. Congress --ossemDiea, mat, ior ine.pur-- .
              pose of establishing the, standard time of the United States, the territory of continental Umted States shall be divided .into five zones
              the manner hereinafter provided. The standard time of the. first zone
              shall be based on the mean 'astronomical time of the second, .zone, on
              the.ninetieth degree; that of the third zone, on the one hundred
              that, of thefourth zone on .the one hundred and twentieth
              degree, ard that of the fifth zone, which shall include only Alaska, on
              the" one hundred and fiftieth' degree. That the limits of "each zone shall
              K AofmaA hv an nrtloi-- nf thp Interstate Commerce Commission, having..
              regard for the convenience f
              commerce and the existing. jucc.tion J
              points and division point 'of common .carriers engaged in commerce-- J
              between the several States' and. with foreign nations, ana sucn oruer
              'may be modified, from time to time. r .
              ? o Tht within the resnective zones created under the" auth
              ority hereof Ihe standard time of the
              all common earners rengagca in- commerce ikhvbm mo kici
              States or between a State and any of the Territories of the United
              State, or'bftween a State or thtfrTerritory of Alaska and any of the,
              insular possessions ottlie United States orany lereim countrytflrf
              all statutes; orders, rules, and regulations relating, io the time,of,-per-- ;
              formance of any act by anyofficer or.department the United States,
              whether in the legislative, executive, or, judicial branches of the Government, or relating to the tinre within which any rights shall accrue
              or determine, or within which any act shall or shall not be performed
              by-an- person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, it shall
              he Understood and intended that the time shall be the United States
              standard, time of the zone within which the act is toibe performed.
              Sec? 3. ThaJ; "at two" o'clock antemeridian of the last Sunday inj
              JIarch of .each year.jhe standard time cacn zone snail De advanced
              one hour, and at two o'clock antemeridian of the last Sunday in
              October in each year the standard time of each zone shall, by the retarding of one hour,-b- returned to the mean astronomical time of the
              degree of longitude governing said zone, that between the last Sunday in March at two o'clock antemeridian and the last Sunday in October at two o'clock' antemeridian in each year the standard time in each
              zone shall be one hour in advance of the mean astronomical time of the
              degree of longitude governing each zone, respectively. )
              Sec. 4. That the standard time of the first zone shall be known
              and designated United States. Eastern Time: that 6f the second zone
              shall be known and Designated as United States Standard Central
              Time; that of the.third zone shall be Known and designated United'
              States Standard Mountain Time; that of the fourth zone shall be
              known and designated as United States Standard Pacific Time; and
              that of the fifth, zone shall be known and designated as United States
              Alaska Time-Se-c;
              5. That, all Acts and parts of Acts in conflict herewith are
              hereby, repealed. .
              Approved March 19, 1918
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87057262/1918-04-01/ed-1/seq-5/#words=act+acts+change+Change+changed+Clock+clock+clocks+daylight+Hour+hour+hours+law+savings+standard+Time+TIME+time</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              What became of that hour between
              2 a. m. and 3 a. m. Easter morning?
              Where did those sixty minutes go
              which were abolished from the face of
              thd earth?
              Thirty-six hundred seconds extermi
              nated when the clocks of America
              were turned ahead.
              Keoktik observed the daylight sav
              ing law Sunday morning by turning
              the clocks ahead one hour. And every
              The earth Is approximately 24,000
              miles around. It makes a full turn in
              twenty-four hours, or travels at the.
              rate of say one thousand miles per
              hour. We poor mortals, clinging to
              the earth as best we can are being
              whirled around at this excessive rate
              of speed. We are going some. Yet
              Sunday morning at 2 o'clock, when the
              clocks were changed, we made an ex
              tra jump of a thousand miles in our
              mad race. Did you notice the change?
              The miser has $200,000 out at inter
              est at six per cent. His income from
              this is $1.37 every hour of the day.
              Sunday morning he made an extra
              $1.37 when the clocks were changed.
              But when the clock is changed iback in
              October, he will lose an equal amount.
              The sick man was to be given a pill
              every half hour. The nurse had been
              instructed to be very careful in fol
              lowing out the instructions. Some
              body changed the clock and she got all
              muddled up as to whether to give the
              dying, man two extra pills. It was a
              case of life and death. The nurse
              fainted and the poor sick man got no
              pills all night long. When the nurse
              regained consciousness, her patient
              had recovered and was out working in
              his war garden.
              The early worm had become tired
              of dodging the early bird every morn
              ing, so the worm made his trips over
              the top an hour earlier each day. But
              the bird observed the new daylight
              savings law and met the worm half
              way as usual.
              A certain man came home at 2
              o'clock. Before retiring he changed'
              the mantle clock. When it struck the
              hour of two he shoved it ahead anoth
              er hour and it struck three. Then he
              went to bed. In the morning his wife
              accused him of coming home at five.
              No argument was allowed. She heard
              t0
              the^cloek strike five. Oh, what's thejold
              The clock In West Keokuk, in
              Lincoln school belfrey. was hanging
              six bells -at seven o'clock Sunday
              morning, one of the few sla-ckers in
              Keokuk. The hands have since been
              changed and the clock is now running
              on war time with the others.
              GATE
              at the co
              caused the man to leave hurriedly, !0f the Y. M. C. A. on Wednesday or recitations from patriotic quota
              leaving a bicycle and four chickens. I evening, April 3, at 8 p. m. The stunt tions.
              three of which had been decapitated. fest has been very successful here- Exercises and drills—Salute to the
              fore
              and
              Vepr's
              darkness of the locality. The chick- cUrIng
              a
              Crowd.
              s. D. Faris,
              of
              the 8Chool
              county
              801^ 'Fever* Thev'^rS "worn the thief was he was a systematic planning for each school of the tennial Tree" is enclosed to each'
              oat before the davis half thro/ They worker for on Friday night a dog be-
              Fish Desert Rhine.
              (By United Press.]
              COUnty
              abie
              gestive programs, planning
              arrived
              at
              prices, area thing of the
              Special Prayer Meetings.
              MONTICEJLLiO. Iowa, April 1.—
              Churches here held special prayer
              meetings yesterday at which suppli
              cations were offered for the allied
              cause and for the failure of the Ger
              man drive on the west front.
              The prayer meetings were called by
              S. Vorhees. They were
              1 —Pnt^rrlb* for TK~
              tain!
              A
              THE DAILY GATE CITE!
              What Became of That Hour
              That Was Lost Sunday Morn?
              Change in Clock Brought
              About Some Interesting
              and Also Embarrasing
              An hour a day gained has its dark
              side as well as its light. For instance
              rent becomes due an hour sooner. We
              are one hour nearer the grave. Life
              and fire insurance expires one hour
              sooner. The thirst parlors in the dry
              towns close one hour earlier. Weeds
              have an exta hour to grow in the gar
              den.
              High noon isn't as high now as It
              was before and midnight is not quite
              so mid.
              The profiteer liaB now another ex
              cuse for raising the price. He can
              ?,mA"°?/"*
              ay
              a®c°,Vnt
              ii OT 3 TV*
              time, etc. etc."
              it is anticipated that this flag. Pledge to the flag. Flag drill.
              will out-rival all others in se- The centennial program as well as
              determined. Whoever centennial celebration, and is circular program, "Planting the Cen-
              the mh 0f
              J. 1- ithe man who stole the chickens. (anniversary of the enabling act of been much in demand as a patriotic
              Bloodless people, thin, anemic people,
              on Aoril 18, 1818, the state speaker during the past few-months, ver H. Cossart, deceased, was filed
              iarge anfl appreciative the.daily program to include salute *t
              schools, is making every effort for simple flag drill to be found in the
              children throughout the school journals.
              to assist in the observance of Planting the Centennial Tree—A
              to arrange and give a suit- teacher, which can be made a very
              centennial and patriotic program interesting part of the program.
              April, which is the: States Attorney Earl W. Wood has,
              congress, on April 18
              centennial commission has
              mended that April 18. 1918, be one to make addresses, including Still
              of the dates to be observed this year,
              1
              become more an l' exercises to be held in the rural dis- yet finds time to give many hours to
              of «sh" is^ie cry utter- tricts in the afternoon or evening, the enlightment of the people of his
              hv ^rLu
              J^he TLeszei^n^ rl I while in the larger schools teachers vicinity along patriotic lines.
              If fdltlom of which have
              evening at
              of the change in
              The biggest change comes around
              midnight. What used to be today Is
              now tomorrow.
              Wonder if a fellow died at 2:30 a.
              m., Sunday, if the life insurance com
              pany couldn't avoid payment by claim
              ing there was no such time?
              A Keokuk policeman on the night
              force left the station one minutes be
              fore two Sunday morning and walked
              city and village in the United States I f^pidly to the union depot He got
              did the same thing. Whatever time it
              is now, it was an hour earlier a day
              ago. One hour of Sunday morning
              must be accounted for somehow, some
              where. Who's got It?
              there at 3:10, an hour and fifteen min
              utes for eight blocks.
              A traveling man who arrived In Keo
              kuk at 2 o'clock Sunday morning and
              walked up the hill to the hotel, found
              that it took him over an hour to make
              the trip. He wiped the perspiration
              from his face and said to the hotel
              clerk: "Whew, I knew that was some
              hill I was climlbing, but I didn't realize
              it was that long."
              If a fire had broken'out in the Estes
              house at 2 o'clock Sunday morning, it
              would have taJcen the department an
              hour to get there. By that time the
              •fire would be beyond control. But it
              didn't.
              Children whose bed time has been
              8:30 o'clock, will have to go to bed
              before it gets dark these evenings.
              That's tough on the kids, but war is
              war.
              Easter Sunday of 1918 can always
              be remembered as having but twenty
              three hours. We used to think Decem
              ber 2,1 was the shortest day of the
              year, but the war has changed many
              things and now Easter is the shortest.
              If shoving the clock ahead one hour
              is such a good thing, why not go a
              little further and shove the calendar
              ahead one month. Why not tear off
              April altogether and have May right
              now, thus avoiding the April show
              ers and have fresh vegetables and
              warmer weather right away? Or go a
              little further and shove the whole
              year ahead. That might see the end
              of the war six months behind. Good
              scheme for somebody with plenty of
              spare time to figure out and suggest
              to Washington.
              Prisoners whose sentences expire
              before October 31, when the clock
              will be pushed back again, have bad
              their sentences reduced by one hour,
              'by the pushing ahead of the clock.
              The chickens held a convention
              Saturday night to see whether they
              would crow by the new time or the
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1927-09-23/ed-1/seq-29/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20&words=Daylight+daylight+daylight-savings+savings+Savings&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=daylight+savings&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              The Daylight Savings Ghost
              Again Rears Its Head
              The ghost of daylight savings once more bobs up.
              Although Congress refused to enact a daylight-savings law
              for the Distrcit just after the war, another attempt may be
              made to obtain congressional consideration for it.
              Voluntarily in force here during the war, daylight savings
              Created such confusion that the proposition to make it
              permanent by law was bitterly fought. Congress, usually delighted to fasten theories upon the District, balked in the face
              of the strong opposition, especially from farmers and farm
              organizations.
              Congress will probably be of the lame, mind this winter if
              a bill for District daylight savings is submitted.
              As a recreation measure, daylight savings is strongly favored,
              but for domestic and business purposes it doesn't stand so
              well. Despite laws in a number of States and cities, passed
              when the daylight savings fad was at its heighth, the scheme
              has made little or no recent progress. The large Eastern
              railroads continue to adhere to standard time throughout the
              year.
              Daylight savings imposes its worst hardships upon city
              housewives and farm and suburban households. Housewives
              enjoy none of its benefits. . Their hours of work, oh the contrary, are lengthened.
              In this city, for example, the mother of a family going to
              work at different hours of the day would be serving breakfast
              at varying hours of the morning to suit the employment hours
              of her husband and children. The boarding housekeeper
              Would be in the same fix.
              The servant problem is another factor that leads to the
              upsetting of domestic routine and family habits. . It was impossible during our trial of daylight savings to
              reconcile working hours in this city. In the Government departments there were different hours of going to work and
              leaving work. This added to the burdens of housekeepers.
              Mothers, with children in schools* were compelled to arouse
              their children an hour earlier than customary, but found it
              almost impossible to get them to bed at night an hour earlier.
              In the opinion of many physicians, mothers and children did
              not get the sleep they were accustomed to and should have.
              The advantages of daylight savings, as viewed by its workings here, were far less than the disadvantages, which included Upset domestic conditions
              —.—
              and considerable chaos.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89074443/1919-09-08/ed-1/seq-6/#date1=1756&index=2&rows=20&words=DAYLIGHT+daylight+savings+SAVINGS&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=daylight+savings&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              THE DAYLIGHT SAVINGS REPEAL
              of the daylight savings repeal over the veto of the
              president has proved the value of organization to farmers.
              Only because the farmers, through their associations, have
              been able to make themselves heard, was the law repealed by con
              gressmen, who want votes in 1920.
              The law, in its two seasons of practice, has proved a hardship
              to workers, who found that the new time worked against farm
              efficiency at a time when farm efficiency was needed as never be
              fore. They found that they had to do their work, because of cli
              matic conditions, under the old time, and do their business under the
              new,time because the business men had turned their clocks ahead.
              As a rule, it failed to help the city worker greatly. The only
              real gainer was the "tired business man," who could get out on the
              golf links for an extra hour every day during the summer.
              Jh® daylight savings law would* never have been repealed
              had it not been for the organized voice of the farmers. Individual
              protests by the farmers would never have availed. The opposition
              to the repeal was organized, too, but not as strongly.
              the farmers, through organization, were able to obtain the
              repeal of this obnoxious act, what is there to prevent them from
              getting other needed legislation through organization that will put
              real farmer representatives in congress and in legislatures?
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86058226/1922-06-09/ed-1/seq-11/#date1=1756&index=6&rows=20&words=daylight+savings&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=daylight+savings&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              DAYLIGHT PLAN IS
              ALLOWED TO STAND
              BY COUNCIL ACTION
              J By refusing to table the ordinance
              repealing the daylight savings plan
              adopted by the city council last Mon
              day night, the city council Thursday
              night allowed the daylight plan to
              stand and to become effective Sunday.
              The ordinance to repeal will have to
              be read a third time, and as council
              dose not meet again until June 19,
              the plan will go into effect before the
              next meeting.. The vote was six to
              five against tabling.
              The ppecial session had been called
              by Mayor Lawrence Handley in view
              of the sentiment against the measure,
              which had been expressed since the
              ordinance was adopted last Monday.
              As a result of the council's action
              Thursday, the daylight savings plan
              will go into effect next Sunday morn
              ing and the ordinance repealing the
              plan will come up for third reading
              Tt the next regular council meeting,
              June 19.
              Council met promptly at 7:30 o'clock
              nnd after being informed by Mayor
              Handley as to the object of the meet
              ing, heard the first reading of an or
              dinance to repeal the daylight savings
              measure. The ordinance was advanc
              ed to second reading immediately,
              Bfter which Louis Salzarulo rose to
              declare against the repeal of the
              measure.
              Against Repeal.
              Salzarulo took the stand that enough
              publicity had been given the ordinance
              establishing the daylight savings plan,
              to that a man living on the Atlantic
              Coast would have had a chance to ex
              press his opinion if he bo desired. He
              felt that unless there was a strong de
              mand on the part of the public the or-
              -finance should not be repealed. .
              - Councilman John E. "White rose. "If
              tre start this hot air business again.
              I'll never get away from hero and I
              im supposed to be out in a few min
              Itec," he said.
              Oentlemen" eald the mayor, "we
              Dan't go any further with the busi
              ness of the meeting until we have a
              motion to dispose of the ordinance."
              "I move the ordinance be tabled,"
              laid Wa'termann, referring to the or
              Sinance to repeal the daylight sav
              ings question.
              A vote to table the ordinance was
              lost, six to five. This means that the
              ordinance to repeal will have to be
              read a third time at the next council
              meeting, and the daylight savings or
              flinance will be in effect starting Sun
              Jay morning.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1937-04-30/ed-1/seq-37/#date1=1756&index=5&rows=20&words=Daylight+daylight+saving+savings+Savings&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=daylight+savings&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              Pupils “Strike” Over Cold Beans j
              Brought by Daylight Savings
              By tne Associated Press.
              CON NERS VTLLE, Ind., April 30.—
              Cold beans and rebellious pupils
              caused the Connersville Education
              Board to order daylight savings time
              yesterday for grade and high schools.
              For two successive days prior to the
              order approximately 75 pupils had
              dropped their books and walked out
              of class rooms an hour early at noon,
              leaving written on bulletin boards in
              large printing, “We don't like cold
              beans.”
              The story back of the cold beans,
              the walkouts and the order involved a
              conflict in daylight savings and Central standard times.
              When daylight savings time went
              into effect a few days ago industrial
              plants here moved their clocks up an
              hour. School authorities, however,
              held to Central standard time.
              Confusion w'as rampant. Every one
              was mixed up.
              Housewives protested vigorously and
              issued ultimatums that they would not
              cook two lunches.
              The sons and daughters suffered in
              the shuffle. Lunches for the dads,
              who worked on daylight saving time,
              were hot; those for the sons and
              daughters, who studied on Central
              standard time, were cold.
              Cold beans one day were not so
              bad. but cold beans every day became
              a bit irksome. The walkouts followed.
              B. E. Myers, high school principal,
              said today members of the Education
              Board had put their heads together
              and decided that perhaps cold beans
              were not so good.
              “The situation was not acute,”
              Myers said. “The pupils thought it
              was fun to walk out of classes an
              hour early at noon. More pupils were
              joining the walkouts every day. The
              School Board thought something
              should be done about it.” 
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1952-09-26/ed-1/seq-52/#date1=1756&index=9&rows=20&words=Daylight+Saving+Savings&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=daylight+savings&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              Extra Hour's Snooze
              Possible Sunday
              As Clocks Change
              District residents can have an extra hoar’s snoose Sunday, if
              they want to stay in bed until the
              last possible minute before it’s
              time to get up for church.
              That’s when clocks win be
              turned back an hour, as Washington returns to Eastern Standard
              Time. Officially, it’s at 2 am., but
              Congress probably didn’t Intend
              for residents to arise at the stroke
              of 2 when it passed the Daylight
              Savings law.
              In fact. Congress mentioned no time. They left that up to the
              Commissioners. The District has
              been on Daylight Saving Time
              since 2 am. April 27.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82014519/1922-05-11/ed-1/seq-10/#date1=1756&index=12&rows=20&words=Daylight+Savings&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=daylight+savings&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87076742/1953-08-07/ed-1/seq-5/#date1=1756&index=16&rows=20&words=Daylight+Savings&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=daylight+savings&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              EASTERN STANDARD TIME—Arid One Hour for Eastern
              Daylight Savings Time. Additional Trips Sunday Afternoons.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045499/1940-04-01/ed-1/seq-8/#date1=1756&sort=relevance&rows=20&words=Daylight+Savings&searchType=basic&sequence=0&index=6&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=daylight+savings&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=2</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              VOTE FOR I
              I THE I
              \TIME CHANGE]
              LiSTE\
              TO
              KIMY
              AT
              0:45
              Tonight
              At preseni all Canadian steamers reach here an hour off our time. i.
              Changing to Seattle time will be of assistance to them, it will give ^
              their lourisis an hour more evening light to see our sights and to visit M
              our shoos. M
              I This is not an untried proposition, Ketchikan changed to Seattle Time |
              | several years ago, and residents there are well pleased with their pres-1
              | ent time. |
              | We urge you to apply the new time to your own life—consider whether |
              | you would like to have the sun set an hour later at the expense of its ris-1
              | ing an hour later than at present. |
              1 WHETHER YOU WOULD LIKE TO UTILIZE IN THE WINTER AF-1
              | TERNOONS, THE SPRING, SUMNER and FALL EVENINGS, that |
              i HOUR of DAYLIGHT now LOST to YOU except in the winter Months! l
              i Would you like an hour's more daylight for recreation every evening, i
              1 together with the other conveniences of having Pacific Coast Time? I
              1 If you would9 then murk your ballot accordingly ... ami g
              VOTE “YES
              ff
              On the Proposal
              | This proposal is noi to be confused with Daylight Savings Time, under which the lime was |
              1 TUsPr^U Proposal Is to Change Ike Time PERMAHEHTLYH *
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1937-05-05/ed-1/seq-7/#date1=1756&sort=relevance&rows=20&words=DAYLIGHT+Daylight+daylight+savings&searchType=basic&sequence=0&index=11&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=daylight+savings&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=2</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              I.C.C. NO FRIEND
              OF DAYLIGHT
              TIME BILL
              Daylight savings time propon
              ents will find no official sympathy
              at the Interstate Commerce Com
              mission, it was learned today.
              It isn’t because officials of that
              agency are not personally inter
              ested in having more time for golf
              or tennis or other daylight activ
              ities, but since it is the duty of
              the I. C. C. to fix the boundaries
              of standard time zones throughout
              the country, its task is being made
              more and more difficult by the
              various States and cities which
              have taken it upon themselves to
              shift the hands of the clock as
              they see fit.
              The I. C. C. does not object
              specifically to the Sacks bill which
              would institute daylight savings
              time in the nation’s capital, but
              looks upon it merely as another
              step in the growing practice of
              making a mockery of the Federal
              statute setting up and maintain
              ing a standard time system.
              This was the explanation given
              today by Thomas E. Payne, ex
              aminer in the office of I. C. C.
              Commissioner Clyde B. Aitchison
              who has charge of standard time
              zone investigations.
              That body now wants Congress
              either to put teeth in the act of
              1918 which set-up daylight sav
              ings time for the entire country—
              since repealed—or to take Con
              gress out of the time regulating
              business.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045499/1949-04-23/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1756&sort=relevance&rows=20&words=Daylight+daylight+Saving+savings&searchType=basic&sequence=0&index=17&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=daylight+savings&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=2</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
              MILLIONS TO
              LOSE I HOUR
              OF SLEEPING
              Many Bin Cities to Adopt
              Daylight Saving Time
              at 2 A.M. Sunday
              NEW YORK, April 23. UP)—About
              50,000.000 Americans will be cheated out of an hour's sleep tonight with the advent of daylight
              savings time.
              Most of the big cities turn their
              clocks ahead cns hoar at 2 a.m. on
              feur.day.
              Residents will have to wait until
              September 25 to get back their
              “lost hour.” At that time clocks
              go back an hour.
              The object of daylight savings
              time is to allow daytime workers
              to enjoy an added hour of daylight after the quitting whistle.
              For that reason it is most popular in heavily-settled areas.
              Large cities going on “fast time"
              include Portland, Me., Boston, Providence, New York, Newark, Philadelphia, Pittsburgh, Baltimore.
              Washington, Cleveland, Chicago, Indianapolis, St. Louis and Portland,
              Oregon.
              Seattle waits until June to change
              i its clocks.
              j* Some cities that had daylight
              savings time a year ago have
              f abandoned it this year. They include Los Angeles, San Francisco,
              Detroit, Chattanooga and Nashville.
              Because farmers’ chores are not
              as closely hitched to the clock,
              most rural areas in the south, the
              middle west and far west shun the
              fast time.
              Radio networks have worked out
              a scheme of their own. Major
              shows will be switched ahead an
              hour in the east so they will be
              heard at the same time. In the
              west and south, they will be rebroadcast an hour later so residents of those areas can hear them
              at the usual time. 
        </text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>